===
＝＝＝
Music playing
音楽の再生
Central Research Institute, October's intellectual lecture, the lecture will begin.
中央研究所、10月の知的講座、開講します。
Let's welcome Wang Yu-Yi, vice president of the committee.
委員会副委員長の王裕毅氏を歓迎しましょう。
Applause
拍手
Good evening, everyone.
皆さん、こんばんわ。
We are very happy to welcome you.
皆様のお越しを心よりお待ち申し上げております。
The director of our Institute of Chemistry is also a researcher
私たちの化学研究所の所長も研究者です
Director Chen Yuru
陳宇如所長
Then Chen Yuru was in 1992
その後、チェン・ユールは1992年に
very young
すごい若い
Graduated from the Department of Chemistry, National Taiwan University in 1992
1992年国立台湾大学化学科卒業
Then I got a Ph.D. in Iowa State in 1997
そして1997年にアイオワ州で博士号を取得しました。
Then go back... worked as a Poster in AMS for a year
それから戻ってください...AMSでポスターとして1年間働きました
Then I went back to Tsinghua University and worked as a Poster for a year
その後、清華大学に戻り、1年間ポスターとして働きました。
to Academia Sinica
中央研究院へ
So the Academia Sinica has been here since 1999
中央研究院は 1999 年からここにあります
Then in 2013 he took over as the director of the Institute of Chemistry
その後、2013 年に化学研究所の所長に就任しました。
It is also in our Academia Sinica
それは私たちの中央研究院にもあります
This few very young
この数人のとても若い人たち
Possibly the youngest director
おそらく最年少監督
also one of the records
これも記録の一つ
Today I see everyone...
今日はみんなに会えるよ…
So excited, there are some high school or junior high school students present
高校生や中学生も来ていてとても興奮しています
This topic is obviously very attractive
このトピックは明らかに非常に魅力的です
he is protein
彼はプロテインです
Protonax
プロトナックス
this protein body
このタンパク質の体
in the last 10 years 20 years
過去10年 20年
It's a very, very popular subject.
とても、とても人気のあるテーマです。
this
これ
Academia Sinica is also good or
中央研究院もいいですし、
various universities
いろいろな大学
A lot of effort has been spent on this
これには多大な労力が費やされてきました
Chenbai City in
チェンバイ市
is used
使用されている
Probably he will mention it later in his speech
おそらく彼は後のスピーチでそれについて言及するでしょう
He uses height
彼は身長を利用する
highly sensitive
非常に敏感な
Phytograph
フィトグラフ
Come
来て
do this
これを行う
Be firm and wait
毅然として待ってください
that app is personalizing
そのアプリはパーソナライズしています
Ling Chuang Proteomics
リン・チュアン プロテオミクス
that hope is practical
その希望は現実的である
We can detect diseases early and
病気を早期に発見することができ、
That is to say, what it actually does
つまり、実際に何をするのかというと、
from basic chemistry
基礎化学から
from the lowest molecular
最低分子から
to understand the causes of disease
病気の原因を理解するために
In the end we hope to be able to
最終的にはできるようになりたいと思っています
reach individual therapy and more
個別のセラピーなどに到達する
So I guess this is also
だからこれもそうだと思う
where so many people are interested
たくさんの人が興味を持っている場所
So its research actually
実際にその研究は
Across chemical biochemical materials, etc.
化学・生化学材料など全般
is rare
珍しいです
We say across many, many fields
私たちは多くの分野にわたってこう言います
and so today it is again
そして今日もまたそうです
in the general public
一般大衆の中で
It should also be possible to understand what it is doing
それが何をしているのかも理解できるはずです
So he's not just in his own
だから彼は自分だけのものではない
In Taiwan, apart from our own people,
台湾では、自国民以外にも、
Of course, what I just said is responsible for some administrative work.
もちろん、私が今言ったようなことは、事務的な仕事の一部を担っています。
and some academic service work
およびいくつかの学術サービス活動
For example, learn, etc.
例えば、勉強するなど。
These must also cover some international organizations
これらは一部の国際機関もカバーする必要があります
So he is also very active internationally
だから彼は国際的にも非常に活躍しています
Of course it will take a lot of time
もちろんかなり時間はかかりますが
So we have to stand with him for another two hours today
だから今日はあと2時間彼と一緒にいなければなりません
I will stop talking nonsense
くだらない話はやめます
Let Dr. Chen start his speech
チェン博士にスピーチを始めてもらいましょう
Colleagues in the hospital
病院の同僚
Hello, everyone outside the hospital.
病院外の皆様、こんにちは。
First of all, I would like to thank Vice President Wang for his introduction.
まず最初に、ご紹介いただきました王副社長に感謝を申し上げたいと思います。
Actually today I
実は今日私は
very very nervous today
今日はとてもとても緊張しています
And I've actually been making slideshows for the past few days
実はここ数日間、スライドショーを作成していました
Because I actually gave a lot of speeches outside in the past
実は私も過去に外でたくさんスピーチをしてきたので、
But most of them are aimed at people in the field of science
しかし、そのほとんどは科学分野の人々を対象としています。
At most, it may be aimed at primary school students, middle school students and college students
せいぜい小学生、中学生、大学生くらいが対象かもしれない
and high school students
そして高校生
But when I received this invitation
しかし、この招待状を受け取ったとき、
They told me that they hope to be able to help the general public
彼らは私に、できるようになりたいと言いました。
that the general public can
一般人ができること
Even people who don't understand our science or biology
私たちの科学や生物学を理解していない人でも
can make them understand
彼らに理解してもらうことができる
It's a big, big challenge for me
それは私にとって大きな、大きな挑戦です
So I actually spent a lot of thinking these days
だから最近は本当にたくさんのことを考えていました
It's just a lot of thinking
それはただ多くのことを考えることです
How can I put this very new theme
この非常に新しいテーマをどのように配置すればよいでしょうか
able to communicate
コミュニケーションができる
then i think i will try my best
それなら頑張ろうと思う
And let me declare
そして宣言させてください
I am in the chemistry department of National Taiwan University this afternoon
今日の午後は国立台湾大学の化学科にいます
I've been in class for three hours
私は3時間授業を受けています
So wait a minute in case the throat breaks
喉が壊れるかもしれないからちょっと待ってください
Please include more
もっと含めてください
If you have a question, you are welcome to raise your hand anytime
質問がある場合は、いつでも手を挙げてください
then i miss everyone
それからみんなに会いたい
when thinking about the average person's perception of protein
平均的な人のプロテインに対する認識を考えるとき
what is the idea
どういう考えですか
Then I did a little test
それからちょっとしたテストをしてみました
I just type protein into that Google
Google にプロテインと入力するだけです
Then check the picture
それから写真を確認してください
I found out a lot of food
たくさんの食べ物を知りました
It's not a test
それはテストではありません
nor treatment
治療もしない
all food
すべての食べ物
What high protein, low protein
なんと高たんぱく、低たんぱく質
good protein bad protein
良いタンパク質悪いタンパク質
So if we take this angle
したがって、この角度を取ると
I'm also starting to think
私も思い始めています
Why the World Health Organization
なぜ世界保健機関なのか
List this protein as the main nutrient for humans
人間の主要栄養素としてこのタンパク質を挙げてください
I don't know if you have thought about this problem
この問題について考えたことがあるかどうかはわかりませんが、
Eating nutrition does not mean
栄養を摂るという意味ではない
You can transform it right away
すぐに変身できますよ
that for protein
それはプロテイン用です
Actually this is a
実はこれは、
very important source of human health
人間の健康の非常に重要な源
because we ate these foods
私たちがこれらの食べ物を食べたからです
This protein is broken down into amino acids
このタンパク質はアミノ酸に分解されます
Amino acids are a
アミノ酸というのは、
the most important ingredient
最も重要な成分
why
なぜ
they will make protein
彼らはタンパク質を作るでしょう
Then our human body has so many vital functions
私たち人間の体には非常に多くの重要な機能があります
Can eat and drink Lassa, can think, can do many, many things
ラッサを食べたり飲んだりできる、考えることができる、たくさんのことができる
In fact, there is a lot of protein to do all kinds of things
実際、あらゆる種類のことを行うためのタンパク質がたくさんあります
including the structure of your body
体の構造も含めて
why can i move my hands
なぜ手を動かすことができるのか
then includes substance delivery
物質の配送も含まれます
then include your metabolism
次に代謝を含めます
You can even think, message transfer, immune regulation, etc.
メッセージ伝達、免疫調節などを考えることもできます。
These are all proteins to do the job
これらはすべて仕事をするためのタンパク質です
But if we look at this biological
しかし、この生物学的観点から見ると、
a so-called one most central criterion
いわゆる最も中心的な基準の 1 つ
We know that the most primitive is from DNA
最も原始的なものは DNA から始まることを私たちは知っています
This molecule starts
この分子は始まります
that DNA it will turn into RNA
そのDNAはRNAに変わります
RNA is turning into protein
RNAがタンパク質に変わる
that in this deep protein process
この深いタンパク質のプロセスにおいて
It is actually a very complicated process
実際には非常に複雑なプロセスです
in the process
過程の中で
There are many factors that make protein expression
タンパク質を発現させる要因は数多くあります
let me explain
ここで説明させてください
The so-called performance refers to the
いわゆるパフォーマンスとは、
Concentration meaning
集中力の意味
its concentration will change
その濃度は変化します
But in the protein factory
しかしタンパク質工場では
in the process of being manufactured
製造途中
It will also have a so-called post-repression modification
いわゆるポスト・リプレッション修正も行われます。
It might add, for example in this example
たとえば、この例では、
under the action of some enzymes
いくつかの酵素の作用下で
protein will be added with some chemical
プロテインには化学物質が添加されます
light energy machine
光エネルギーマシン
For example, this is a
たとえば、これは
a chemical molecule of pro-acid
プロ酸の化学分子
After adding these light energy machines
これらの光エネルギーマシンを追加した後
It's as if these proteins are spliced
まるでこれらのタンパク質がスプライシングされているかのようです
so-called antenna
いわゆるアンテナ
It will be identified by many, many actions
それは多くのアクションによって識別されます
Then we can't help but ask a question
それなら質問せずにはいられない
Among so many biomolecules
非常に多くの生体分子の中で
who is the most important thing
一番大切なものは誰ですか
who is primarily to perform the function of the organism
この生物の機能を主に実行するのは誰ですか
Is it DNA?
DNAですか？
Is it RNA or protein?
それはRNAですか、それともタンパク質ですか？
I don't announce the answer
答えは発表しません
please think about it
考えてみてください
Let's start with an interesting question
興味深い質問から始めましょう
i like reading philosophy
私は哲学を読むのが好きです
I have read many theories
たくさんの理論を読みました
what is human existence
人間の存在とは何か
is the physical existence
物理的な存在です
or are you in fact just everything invisible
それとも実際には目に見えないものだけですか？
just you see this guy
ただあなたはこの男を見ます
Just an image of your brainwaves
あなたの脳波の単なるイメージ
So the biologists
それで生物学者たちは
What they must believe is the so-called
彼らが信じなければならないのは、いわゆる
Balvin's theory of evolution
バルビンの進化論
This is the person from this
この人はここからの人です
Slowly evolve from the source
ソースはゆっくりと進化しました
But if you are religious
しかし、もしあなたが宗教的であれば、
you may feel god
あなたは神を感じるかもしれません
He is the biggest commander
彼は最大の指揮官だ
God created everything
神はすべてを創造しました
create everything
すべてを創造する
I also read science books
科学の本も読みます
He said that some people think that in fact many
彼は、一部の人々は実際には多くの人がそう考えていると述べた
Our physical existence is a TV wave
私たちの物理的な存在はテレビの電波です
There's just one brain center to direct
指揮すべき脳中枢は 1 つだけ
so we're going to answer
だから私たちは答えます
who am i
私は誰
the simplest
もっとも単純な
What we learned from textbooks
教科書から学んだこと
Everyone agrees
誰もが同意する
The origin of life is from DNA
生命の起源はDNAから
DNA is actually a very mysterious combination
DNAって実はとても不思議な組み合わせなんです
It only has four monomer ATGCs in total
モノマー ATGC は合計 4 つだけです
But these four monomers
しかし、これら 4 つのモノマー
will become tangled into very
非常に巻き込まれるだろう
a very long molecule
非常に長い分子
Then in order to solve this problem
それでは、この問題を解決するために
In fact, in the past ten or twenty years
実はここ10年、20年の間に
There's a very, very important scientific advance
非常に重要な科学の進歩があります
then let me introduce to you
それでは紹介させてください
If we look at the composition of a person
人の構成を見てみると
we know everyone
私たちはみんなを知っています
you have about six trillion cells
約6兆個の細胞がある
Each person has twenty-three pairs of chromosomes
各人は 23 対の染色体を持っています
Twenty-two pairs of normal chromosomes
22対の正常な染色体
The other pair are the so-called sex chromosomes
もう一方のペアはいわゆる性染色体です
Then your chromosomes usually come from your mother
そうすると、あなたの染色体は通常母親から来ます
usually from your dad
普通はお父さんから
But have you ever thought about a question
しかし、質問について考えたことはありますか
if this your chromosome
これがあなたの染色体なら
All from Mom and Dad
全てはお父さんとお母さんから
Why Siblings Are So Different
なぜ兄弟はこんなに違うのか
regardless of intelligence
知性とは関係なく
regardless of your appearance
あなたの外見に関係なく
In fact, many brothers and sisters are not alike at all.
実際、多くの兄弟姉妹はまったく似ていません。
Then in order to understand this problem
それでは、この問題を理解するために
around 1988
1988年頃
Please go back to that long time ago in history
歴史の遠い昔に戻ってください
At that time it didn't matter
あの時は関係なかった
There is this concept of computer
コンピューターという概念があります
Then in the 1980s
それから1980年代には
Gene sequencing work begins
遺伝子配列決定作業が始まる
So, some people started to think
それで、何人かの人々は考え始めました
Now that I can sequence the genes
これで遺伝子の配列がわかるようになりました
i will explain later
後で説明します
Then can we put human
じゃあ人間を入れてもいいかな
This complex genome solves it all
この複雑なゲノムがすべてを解決します
The idea of ​​Echo
エコーの考え方
is a department called the U.S. Department of Energy
米国エネルギー省と呼ばれる部門です
The U.S. Department of Energy is a
米国エネルギー省は、
very very rich research unit
非常に豊富な研究ユニット
Okay, when you think about energy, it means oil.
さて、エネルギーについて考えるとき、それは石油を意味します。
they are early
彼らは早いです
they are doing a lot of drilling for oil
彼らは石油を掘るためにたくさんの掘削を行っています
so they will prop up a lot
だから彼らはたくさん支えてくれるでしょう
so-called interesting project
いわゆる面白いプロジェクト
Even a plan that everyone thinks is impossible
誰もが不可能だと思う計画でも
as long as it's interesting they'll go to the props
それが面白い限り、彼らは小道具に行きます
So in 1988 when
それで1988年のとき、
DOE
エネルギー省
that combines in the United States for this biomedical field
この生物医学分野のために米国で組み合わせたもの
a very important research institution
非常に重要な研究機関
National Institutes of Health
国立衛生研究所
their two units
2つのユニット
First started with such an idea
まずはそんな発想からスタート
Can we take two or three pairs of human chromosomes
ヒトの染色体を2対または3対採取できますか?
corresponding to this gene
この遺伝子に対応する
can you solve it all
すべて解決できますか
Of course everyone thought it was an impossible task at the time.
もちろん当時は誰もがそれは不可能なことだと考えていました。
no one thought it would work
誰もそれがうまくいくとは思わなかった
Then this Selera company
それからこのセレラ社
It's a private biotech company
民間のバイオテクノロジー企業です
Then they later showed the possibility of commercial interests
その後、彼らは商業的利益の可能性を示しました
So in 1997 they
それで1997年に彼らは
joined the program
プログラムに参加しました
I didn't expect that in the process
途中でそんなことになるとは思わなかった
Everyone can finally solve this problem with gene sequencing
遺伝子配列決定により、ついに誰もがこの問題を解決できるようになりました
Then let me explain a little bit here. This is actually a very interesting method.
それでは、ここで少し説明させていただきますが、これは実は非常に興味深い方法です。
This genetic sequencing is called the submachine gun method.
この遺伝子配列決定はサブマシンガン法と呼ばれます。
Sharkoon is that submachine gun
シャークーンはサブマシンガンです
Submachine guns in the movie
映画に出てくるサブマシンガン
Then his methodology is actually relying on some coal
彼の方法論は実際には石炭に依存している
This coal is also a protein
この石炭もタンパク質です
That coal is like a submachine gun
その石炭はサブマシンガンのようなものです
He only sees only DNA
彼にはDNAしか見えていない
he cut it up
彼はそれを切り取った
So why is he called submachine gun method
ではなぜ彼はサブマシンガン法と呼ばれるのか
that in the process of chopping and chopping
それは刻んで刻む途中です
i just mentioned
先ほど言いました
The era sequenced
時代は順番に並んだ
This methodology for gene sequencing just came out
遺伝子配列決定のためのこの方法論は発表されたばかりです
so what
だから何
As long as we can get this
これが手に入る限りは
The sequence of each small fragment solves it
それぞれの小さな断片の配列がそれを解決します
it has many many many paragraphs
たくさんのたくさんの段落があります
OK, after I solve it
OK、解決したら
I then find out which fragments are overlapping
次に、どの断片が重なっているかを見つけます
or if the same
または同じ場合
There should be a part of the sequence that should be repeated
シーケンスの一部を繰り返す必要があります
So you by this example
つまり、この例ではあなたは
you can see this paragraph
この段落を見ることができます
There are 4 ACGAs here
ここには 4 つの ACGA があります
It is the same as the following ACGA4
以下のACGA4と同じです
So it is possible that this paragraph will be connected with this paragraph.
したがって、この段落とこの段落が接続される可能性があります。
In the same way, I can put the same
同様に、同じように置くことができます
I'll pick it up again
また拾ってみます
So using these three paragraphs
したがって、これらの 3 つの段落を使用すると、
I can piece together a long paragraph
長い段落をつなぎ合わせることができる
by analogy
那依使類推
You can push it piece by piece
部分ごとに押し込むことができます
finally hook it up
最後に接続します
ok but i want to stress
わかりましたが、強調したいのは
this is a very long sequence
これは非常に長いシーケンスです
Okay, so here's a lot of multigene sequencing
さて、ここに多重遺伝子配列決定の多くがあります
Biological information beyond tools
ツールを超えた生体情報
computer information
コンピュータ情報
In fact, it is a very important one in this project.
実は、これはこのプロジェクトにおいて非常に重要なものです。
a component
一個component
So bioinformatics was also at that time
バイオインフォマティクスも当時はそうだった
Start a lot of this derivative
この派生商品をたくさん始めてください
Didn't think it was about 15 years
15年も経つとは思わなかった
We actually sequenced the human genome
私たちはヒトゲノムを解読しました
After that, of course, one after another
もちろんその後も続々と
Some other countries have joined
他にもいくつかの国が参加しています
So later everyone found out that
それで後でみんなが気づいたのですが、
People are so complicated, everyone is different
人間はとても複雑で、誰もが異なります
In fact, he doesn't have that many genes.
実際、彼はそれほど多くの遺伝子を持っていません。
About 30,000 functional copies of this gene
この遺伝子の機能的コピーは約 30,000 個
Then after the gene sequencing is completed
そして、遺伝子配列決定が完了した後、
Many upgrade companies have been produced one after another
数多くのアップグレード企業が続々と誕生
Chip company Gene testing company
チップ会社 遺伝子検査会社
everyone thinks
誰もが思う
After this periodic table
この周期表以降
I personally think
個人的には思う
This is probably the most important thing in the history of human science
これはおそらく人類科学の歴史の中で最も重要な出来事です
We've solved the genetic jigsaw puzzle
私たちは遺伝的ジグソーパズルを解きました
So everyone thinks that after having this gene
この遺伝子を持った後は誰もがこう思います
Because the gene produces RNA to produce Portin
遺伝子がポーチンを生成するためのRNAを生成するため
After this blueprint we should all things
この青写真の後、すべてのことを行う必要があります
all problems can be solved
すべての問題は解決できる
all the secrets we should be able to know
私たちが知るべきすべての秘密
why is there life why is there disease
なぜ生命があるのか​​ なぜ病気があるのか
But is it true?
しかし、それは本当でしょうか？
Then after the genetic sequencing of this human
その後、この人間の遺伝子配列が解析された後、
A new field has emerged called genomics
ゲノミクスという新しい分野が登場
Well, the gene is a segment
そうですね、遺伝子はセグメントです
This is called gene
これを遺伝子といいます
Genome means
ゲノムとは
I'm going to study all the genes, this is called the gene body
私はすべての遺伝子を研究するつもりです、これは遺伝子本体と呼ばれます
I'm going to learn about all the structures
あらゆる構造に​​ついて勉強していきます
I'm going to find out what it does
それが何をするのか調べてみます
This is called genomics
これをゲノミクスといいます
Here are some students here to explain
ここで何人かの学生が説明します
A gene means a single
遺伝子とは単一のものを意味します
Then if you see this OME, it means all the components
この OME が表示された場合、それはすべてのコンポーネントを意味します
This is called GENOME
これをゲノムといいます
Then add ICS to represent the knowledge of what to study
次に、学習内容の知識を表す ICS を追加します。
So you'll hear a lot of GENOMICS
ジェノミクスについてたくさん聞くことになるでしょう
POTENOMICS METAPOLOMICS
ポテノミクス メタポロミクス
What do they represent?
それらは何を表しているのでしょうか？
There is even a company in Taiwan called
台湾にもこんな会社があります。
Physical science companies are studying these
物理科学企業はこれらを研究しています
Then after the genetic sequencing of this human
その後、この人間の遺伝子配列が解析された後、
One after another there are many important
重要なことが次々と出てきます
The species sequencing of this animal was also done
この動物の種の配列も決定されました
then you may feel
そうすればあなたは感じるかもしれません
why not our cutest puppy
なぜ私たちの一番かわいい子犬ではないのですか
cats because they are not animal models
猫は動物モデルではないので
Then you can see things like worms, mice, etc.
すると、ミミズやネズミなどが見えてきます。
These are zebrafish
これらはゼブラフィッシュです
These are very important for biomedical research
これらは生物医学研究にとって非常に重要です
an animal pattern
動物柄
So these are sequenced
したがって、これらは順序付けされています
In the process, a very interesting question arises
その過程で非常に興味深い疑問が生じます
In theory this could be one of the most important discoveries in human history
理論的には、これは人類の歴史の中で最も重要な発見の 1 つである可能性があります
we make money from it
私たちはそれでお金を稼いでいます
And this guy Gray Venter
そしてこの男、グレイ・ヴェンター
is what I just mentioned
それは私が今言ったことです
The president of this company at Stellera
ステラエラのこの会社の社長
then why did he join
ではなぜ彼は参加したのか
because he finds it profitable
彼はそれが利益になると思っているから
So then he brought up
それで彼は言いました
should go to the result of this sequence
このシーケンスの結果に移動する必要があります
apply for patent
特許を申請する
Everyone who wants to use it has to pay
使いたい人は全員料金を支払わなければなりません
That is to believe that he lost
それは彼が負けたと信じることだ
Because everyone thinks that human genes
なぜなら、人間の遺伝子は誰もがそう思っているからです。
belongs to all
全員に属する
It should not be used for commercial interests
商業的利益のために使用すべきではありません
So he lost
それで彼は負けた
he lost to him
彼は彼に負けた
Everyone thinks it should be shared
誰もが共有すべきだと考えている
so the same human protein
つまり同じ人間のタンパク質
Once completed in the future
将来完成したら
also belong to all mankind
すべての人類のものでもあります
Everyone in our field feels that
私たちの分野の誰もがそう感じています
This should belong to all mankind
これは全人類のものであるべきです
a blessing of
的一個福祉
but at the same time
しかし同時に
He also did a very interesting thing
彼はまた非常に興味深いことをしました
Then in 2000 when he
そして2000年に彼は
publishes his own personal sequence
彼自身の個人的なシーケンスを公開します
then why did i bring it up
ではなぜそれを持ち出したのか
Because after about seven or eight years of this process
なぜなら、このプロセスを7、8年ほど続けた後だからです。
In fact, the tools for gene sequencing are becoming more and more mature.
実際、遺伝子配列決定のためのツールはますます成熟してきています。
so you can imagine
想像できるように
I personally at least believe
私は個人的に少なくとも信じています
one day
ある日
You may want to see if there is anything wrong with your body
身体に異常がないか確認してみると良いでしょう
you originally had a gene
あなたはもともと遺伝子を持っていました
may be able to tell you
あなたに伝えることができるかもしれません
The state of your body now
今の体の状態
So this is a very important development
これは非常に重要な開発です
But after gene sequencing is complete
しかし、遺伝子配列が解かれた後は、
do we solve all the problems
すべての問題は解決しますか
I would like to introduce two important people here
ここで二人の重要な人物を紹介したいと思います
an important person black star our ten group
大切な人 ブラックスター 僕らの10グループ
I don't need to introduce
紹介する必要はないよ
there is another
もう一つの...がある
This is my college classmate
これは私の大学の同級生です
Researcher Lin Zhiming
林志明研究員
He is now at the Fate Institute of Academia Sinica
彼は現在、中央研究院運命研究所に所属しています。
He is a disciple of Dean Li Yuanzhe
彼は李元哲学部長の弟子です
he is super
彼はスーパーだ
He is doing this in the atmosphere
彼は雰囲気の中でこれをやっています
This environment-related molecule
この環境関連分子は
so he is my idol
だから彼は私のアイドルです
My classmates have been great since before
クラスメイトは昔から仲がよかった
Excuse me
すみません
How similar are these two people
この二人はどのくらい似ていますか
don't be afraid
恐れないでください
I asked Lin Zhiming for permission
林志明に許可を求めました
so don't be afraid
だから恐れないでください
Lin Zhiming agreed
林志明も同意した
he heard this too
彼もこれを聞いた
I did this
これは私がしました
Because he first asked me to teach high school students
最初は高校生を教えて欲しいと頼まれたので
I said can I be kidding
冗談でいいですかって言いました
say no problem
問題ないと言う
He's so smart that the black star
彼は黒星になるほど賢い
I think Lin Zhiming is at least much handsomer than him
林志明は少なくとも彼よりずっとハンサムだと思う
Does anyone want to take a guess please ask you
推測したい人はいますか？
How similar are their genes
彼らの遺伝子はどれくらい似ているのか
99.5
９９。５
Then I believe that many people here must have studied statistics.
それから、ここにいる多くの人は統計を勉強したことがあると思います。
Is there any student or person who can tell me
教えてくれる学生さんや人はいますか？
In the case of statistically two standard deviations
統計的に標準偏差が 2 つの場合
What is the percentage of similarity between two objects
2 つのオブジェクト間の類似性のパーセンテージは何ですか
We call these two things the same
私たちはこれら 2 つのことを同じと呼びます
Can anyone tell me that students should be able to
学生は次のことができるべきだと誰か教えてください。
More than 90
90以上
how many 90
いくつ 90
My students can't answer
生徒たちは答えられない
i say it again
もう一度言います
That is to say, statistically we often say
つまり、統計的に私たちはよくこう言います。
With a probability of 95.5 percent
95.5パーセントの確率で
We call these two things the same
私たちはこれら 2 つのことを同じと呼びます
So in statistics, 95.5 is the same as we think
つまり、統計では、95.5 は私たちが考えているのと同じです。
So if from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
the answer is 98
答えは98です
So from a practical point of view
したがって、実用的な観点からすると、
98% of human DNA is exactly the same as stars
人間のDNAの98%は星と全く同じ
Then if you talk about statistics
それから統計について話すなら
they are the same
彼らは同じです
But you know it's totally different
でも、それは全く違うのは知っていますよね
the next question
次の質問
if the same person
同じ人なら
How similar is this gene
この遺伝子はどれくらい似ていますか
let me explain
説明させてください
This is the most handsome man in the world in my opinion
私の意見では、この人が世界で最もハンサムな男性です
And this is the smartest in the world I think
そして、これが世界で最も賢いと私は思います
I adore him so much
私は彼をとても愛しています
so he is my alien
だから彼は私の宇宙人です
I also believe
私も信じています
Of course Lin Zhiming is still very good
もちろん林志明は今でもとても上手です
How similar are these three people?
この3人はどのくらい似ていますか?
We just said that people are 98 times worse than stars
人間は星よりも98倍悪いと言ったばかりです
How different are the three
3つはどれくらい違うのか
just that answer
それだけの答え
99.9
９９。９
So here comes an interesting question:
ここで興味深い質問が生まれます。
the three of them totally
三人とも完全に
not related to
関係ない
but their genes
しかし彼らの遺伝子は
Up to 99.9% similarity
最大 99.9% の類似性
So if you and your brothers and sisters
それで、あなたとあなたの兄弟姉妹なら
you can imagine
想像できるでしょう
You feel more similar
あなたはもっと似ていると感じます
But why are people so different
しかし、なぜ人はこれほどまでに異なるのでしょうか
good
良い
Here I list
ここにリストします
several fragments of genes
遺伝子のいくつかの断片
one of them
それらの中の一つ
one of them is
そのうちの1人は
The Genes of the Mediterranean Type
地中海型の遺伝子
I don't know everyone's eyes
みんなの目は分からない
Can you see the difference?
違いが分かりますか？
one of them is
そのうちの1人は
mediterranean critique
地中海形評學
different from others
他の人とは違う
here
ここ
good
良い
so everyone can see
みんなが見れるように
at this place
この場所で
this place is different
ここは違う
good
良い
so say
だから、言って
genetically similar
遺伝的に似ている
but why
しかし、なぜ
a defect in a gene or two
1つまたは2つの遺伝子の欠陥
on the contrary, it will make a big difference
逆にそれは大きな違いを生みます
mediterranean typology
地中海の類型学
Then I'll give another one
じゃあもう一つあげるよ
more extreme example
もっと極端な例
we know say
私たちは言うことを知っています
My biology is not good
私の生態は良くありません
But we know that butterflies have
しかし、私たちは蝶が持っていることを知っています
From passing through the egg, no, it should be the egg, right?
卵の先から、いや、卵のはずですよね？
egg, from brave to heavy
卵、勇敢なものから重いものまで
it has undergone such a transformation
このような変化を遂げてきました
But if you look at its genome,
しかし、そのゲノムを見てみると、
The genome of these four periods is completely unchanged
これら 4 つの期間のゲノムは完全に変化していない
are exactly the same
全く同じです
So there seems to be some problem here
したがって、ここで何らかの問題が発生しているようです
we are not able to answer
私たちは答えることができません
it goes through if all the same
すべて同じであれば通過します
why is it so different
なぜそんなに違うのか
No matter its shape, no matter its whole state
形に関係なく、全体の状態に関係なく
is completely different
全く違います
So in the process
それでその過程で
let me explain
説明させてください
We know that DNA turns into RNA
DNAがRNAに変化することはわかっています
that makes protein from RNA
RNAからタンパク質を作る
That's because each DNA transfer process to RNA
それは、DNA から RNA への各転移プロセスが行われるためです。
It each this password is fixed
このパスワードはそれぞれ固定です
ATGC must be the same for everyone
ATGC は誰にとっても同じである必要があります
So theoretically once the DNA is fixed,
つまり、理論的には、DNAが固定されると、
It produces proteins that are also immobilized
同じく固定化されたタンパク質を生成します
Because every RNA code
なぜなら、あらゆるRNAコードは
will produce the same amino acid
同じアミノ酸を生成します
That's why
それが理由です
Just for this example
この例だけですが
Why did the DNA sequence change after
なぜその後DNA配列が変化したのか
mediterranean selection
地中海セレクション
The reason is that
その理由は、
When this gene is mutated
この遺伝子が変異すると
For example, this is a normal gene
たとえば、これは正常な遺伝子です
Then these two produce
そして、この二人が生み出すのは、
should produce this amino acid
このアミノ酸を生成する必要があります
But what happens when your genetic mutation
しかし、遺伝子変異が起こるとどうなるでしょうか
It starts from this amino acid
このアミノ酸から始まります
into this amino acid of Valorin
バロリンのこのアミノ酸に
This position happens to be the protein
この位置はまさにプロテイン
This hemoglobin is combined with oxygen
このヘモグロビンが酸素と結びついて、
it's in our blood
それは私たちの血の中にある
is responsible for carrying oxygen
酸素を運ぶ役割を担っている
This location happens to be
この場所はたまたま
The position where this protein binds to the oxygen species
このタンパク質が酸素種と結合する位置
In other words, the point
つまり、ポイントは、
because the structure of the protein has changed
タンパク質の構造が変化したため
So it produces Mediterranean type selection
したがって、地中海タイプの選択が生成されます
So from this example tell us that
この例から次のことが分かります
Actually the protein it is really going to perform
実際に実際に機能するプロテイン
An important function of a molecule
分子の重要な機能
genes are stable
遺伝子は安定している
protein is the active
活動するのはたんぱく質
to help you perform functions
機能の実行を支援するため
So after genomics
ゲノミクスの後は
A new field has emerged
新しい分野が現れました
protein body
プロテインボディ
I think I probably know all about protein.
プロテインについてはおそらく詳しいと思います。
that proteosome
そのプロテオソーム
means all protein
すべてのタンパク質を意味します
This is called protein body
これをプロテインボディといいます
what about this concept
このコンセプトはどうですか
it was 1994
1994年でした
by this from Australia
オーストラリアからのこれで
Professor Marco Wilken
Marco Wilken教授
first proposed
最初に提案された
But I'm here to tell you
でも、私はあなたに伝えるためにここにいます
when he brought it up
彼がそれを持ち出したとき
It's his first year of doctoral class
博士課程の1年目です
the age of his students
彼の生徒の年齢
So he still looks like this
だから彼は今もこんな姿をしている
This is his current photo
これが彼の現在の写真です
He's younger than me at the right age
彼は適切な年齢で私よりも若いです
The appearance of this proteosome
このプロテオソームの様子
In fact, he wants to respond
実際、彼はそれに応えたいのです
we want to understand
私たちは理解したいのです
These are the ones that actually perform the function
これらは実際に機能を実行するものです
these proteins
これらのタンパク質
we want to analyze him
私たちは彼を分析したいと思っています
So we gave him a
そこで私たちは彼に
protein body
プロテインボディ
So we want to understand
だから私たちは理解したいのです
all protein
すべてのタンパク質
That field is analyzing
その分野は分析しています
or what are you looking at
それとも何を見ているのですか
for example
例えば
We want to understand the different states
さまざまな状態を理解したい
Behavior of the protein Has its concentration changed?
タンパク質の挙動 濃度は変化しましたか?
Especially cancer, which we'll get to later.
特に癌については後ほど説明します。
Many cancers are caused by protein concentration
がんの多くはタンパク質の濃度によって引き起こされる
abnormal increase
異常増加
or after generation
あるいは世代以降
Post-repression modification of this protein
このタンパク質の抑制後の修飾
Did it add some special light energy machine
特別な光エネルギーマシンを追加したのか
Like Linghua or like Zhongyuanyuan
凌華みたいな、あるいは中遠源みたいな
a very important area
非常に重要な領域
Glycosylation Glycosylation
グリコシル化
Added some specific sugar molecules
いくつかの特定の糖分子を追加しました
The entire protein structure and its function are all changed.
タンパク質全体の構造とその機能がすべて変化します。
even protein measurements
タンパク質の測定や計測も
It is the structure of three degrees and four degrees
3度4度の構造です
And protein is actually very similar to people
そしてタンパク質は実際には人間と非常によく似ています
According to the research in the project play
プロジェクトプレイの調査によると
70% of protein is with other people
タンパク質の70％は他の人と一緒にあります
it doesn't exist alone
それは単独では存在しません
like human society
人間社会と同じように
Then it likes three to five friends best
そうすると、3人から5人の友達が一番好きになる
So in East
それで東では
About three to five proteins are aggregated together
3～5個程度のタンパク質が集まったもの
So this is also a very interesting thing
ということで、これも非常に興味深いことなのですが、
its not a singles
シングルスではない
it's actually a group
それは実際にはグループです
Let's do something together
一緒に何かやりましょう
Let's give an example
例を挙げてみましょう
with this history
この歴史とともに
If you go for a cancer test today
今日がん検査に行くなら
Is it DNA?
DNAですか？
mostly protein
ほとんどタンパク質
This is where you go to the hospital
ここが病院に行くところです
during this cancer screening
今回のがん検診の際に
a some protein
いくつかのタンパク質
have some protein
プロテインを持ってください
it has high professionalism
高いプロ意識を持っています
For example, this liver cancer
例えば、この肝臓がん
Not recommended
推奨されません
This is an embryonic protein
これは胚性タンパク質です
when your concentration
あなたの集中力が高いとき
this egg white is interesting
この卵白は面白いです
its when a woman is pregnant
それは女性が妊娠しているときです
when the fetus
胎児のとき
This concentration is very high
この濃度は非常に高いです
After birth, however, the concentration decreases
しかし、産後は集中力が低下します。
But when this protein concentration
しかし、このタンパク質濃度になると、
Just be careful when raising
ただ育てるときは気をつけてください
You are at risk for cancer
あなたはがんのリスクにさらされています
another prostate cancer
別の前立腺がん
There are also relatively specialized proteins
比較的特殊なタンパク質もあります
There are some so-called screening proteins
いわゆるスクリーニングタンパク質がいくつかあります
This is the number of the protein
これはタンパク質の数です
that you are in many different
あなたはいろいろなところにいますか
These concentrations are elevated in cancer
がんではこれらの濃度が上昇します
So the doctor will tell you that in case of misfortune
それで医者は不幸な場合にこう言います
Your concentration increases
集中力が高まります
He'll tell you to watch, screen, etc.
彼はあなたに、見る、スクリーンするなどと言います。
But you can also see from here
でもここからも見えますよ
still many important cancers
重要ながんはまだたくさんある
e.g. lung cancer
例：肺がん
No detected molecules at all
分子はまったく検出されませんでした
the other one
別のもの
just is the detection point of view
あくまで検出の観点です
from a therapeutic point of view
治療的な観点から
Protein is also the most important
たんぱく質も一番大事
target molecule
標的分子
that is outside the sin of the cell
それは細胞の罪の外にある
we call the top of the cell membrane
細胞膜の上部を私たちは細胞膜と呼びます
on the cell membrane
細胞膜の上に
There are so many important glycoproteins
重要な糖タンパク質がたくさんあります
Membrane Protein
膜タンパク質
then they are often
それから彼らはしばしば
double as this material transport
この物質輸送の2倍
especially the function of drug delivery
特にドラッグデリバリーの機能
Then they also receive messages from the outside world.
そして、外の世界からのメッセージも受け取ります。
And then also they're doing a lot of molecular
そしてまた、彼らは多くの分子研究を行っています
Identify a very important protein
非常に重要なタンパク質を特定する
So if you look at this treatment this statistic
この治療法を見ると、この統計は
Let me explain a little bit here
ここで少し説明させてください
This is the article
これがその記事です
he went to count
彼は数えに行きました
Probably nearly 500 different drugs in clinical practice
おそらく500近くの異なる薬剤が臨床現場で使用されている
Then it counts who these drugs are aimed at.
次に、これらの薬物が誰を対象としているかをカウントします。
come do this go be a goal
さあ、これを目標にしてください
Then you can see that the DNA is very small
すると DNA が非常に小さいことがわかります
only here
ここだけ
Everything else is protein
それ以外はたんぱく質です
all of them
それらすべて
So if you're looking at this receptor
この受容体を見ていると
It's a receptor for a receiving protein called messaging
メッセージングと呼ばれる受信タンパク質の受容体です
Those are all cell membrane proteins
これらはすべて細胞膜タンパク質です
Probably we can say that more than 70% of the drugs
おそらく、薬物の 70% 以上が
All target membrane proteins of cell membranes
細胞膜のあらゆる標的膜タンパク質
The most famous one is GPCR
最も有名なものはGPCRです
receptor protein
受容体タンパク質
They are widely used in
それらは広く使用されています
various diseases
さまざまな病気
So from the detection point of view
検出の観点から見ると
From a Drug Development Perspective
医薬品開発の観点から
Proteins are very important class of molecules
タンパク質は非常に重要な分子です
that in the process
その過程で
it actually
それは実際に
But it compares to DNA
しかし、それはDNAと比較します
It's actually a very complicated process
実際には非常に複雑なプロセスです
Then I have a protein with this
じゃあこれでプロテインを飲むよ
It's called EGF
EGFといいます
This is currently in lung cancer and breast cancer
これは現在、肺がんと乳がんです
target especially lung cancer
特に肺がんをターゲットにする
Most important most important target protein
最も重要な最も重要な標的タンパク質
So this is a protein structure
これはタンパク質の構造です
This circle represents the protein structure
この円はタンパク質の構造を表します
This place represents the cell membrane
この場所は細胞膜を表します
It's a protein stuck in the cell membrane
細胞膜にくっついたたんぱく質です
that's outside the cell membrane
それは細胞膜の外側です
it has a lot of sugar programs
砂糖プログラムがたくさんあります
these are sugar
これらは砂糖です
Then everyone already knows, not everyone
それなら誰もがすでに知っていますが、誰もが知っているわけではありません
This is Dean Wen's discovery
これはディーン・ウェンの発見です
they found out
彼らは知った
EGF outside the cell membrane
細胞膜の外にあるEGF
If there is this Syllation
このシレーションがあれば
dehydrated acid sugar
脱水酸糖
or sugar like Fucose
またはフコースのような砂糖
it will suppress
それは抑制するだろう
This EGF
このEGFは
This protein is activated
このタンパク質が活性化されると、
That's more complicated
それはもっと複雑です
outside changed
外側が変わった
It actually affects the inside
実は内部にも影響を及ぼしているのです
The P stands for the message transmission of acidification
P は酸性化のメッセージ伝達を表します。
This is currently the most important mechanism for message delivery
これは現在、メッセージ配信のための最も重要なメカニズムです
Then they found that once the outside sugar was suppressed
すると、外側の糖分が抑制されることが分かりました。
It also causes EGF
EGFの原因にもなる
The probability that this protein is activated
このタンパク質が活性化される確率
But what is interesting is our experience
しかし、興味深いのは私たちの経験です
When Dean Wen told us at that time
そのときディーン・ウェンがこう語った。
I think such an important goal
とても重要な目標だと思う
Should be clear here
ここで明確にする必要があります
in fact not yet
実際にはまだです
so exaggerated
とても誇張された
I think it's exaggerated
それは誇張されていると思います
Such an important target therapy
非常に重要な標的療法
But the above structure
しかし、上記の構造は、
The underlying structure is currently unclear
基本的な構造は現時点では不明です
How does it affect the two
それは二人にどう影響するのか
Actually still not clear
実はまだはっきりしていない
that in terms of it
それに関しては
Why are these targets
なぜこれらがターゲットなのか
Why These Membrane Proteins Are Important
これらの膜タンパク質が重要な理由
because once it is stimulated
一度刺激されると
it initiates what is called messaging
いわゆるメッセージングを開始します
like we're running a relay race
まるで駅伝をしているかのように
protein one by one
プロテインをひとつずつ
Many times in this race it has to take over
このレースでは何度もテイクオーバーしなければならない
It is through this spiritual acidification
それはこの精神的な酸性化によるものです
Once acidified by the spirit it knows
スピリットによって酸性化されると、それは知っています
I'm coming to take over
引き継ぎに来ます
those messages
それらのメッセージ
once it happens it's bad
そうなったらダメだよ
sometimes there are some roads
時々道もあるよ
it causes cell growth
それは細胞の成長を引き起こします
But if cancer cells grow
しかし、がん細胞が増殖すると、
that would be bad, cause cancer
それは悪いことだ、ガンの原因になる
so how to find out
それでどうやって調べるか
The process of this message passing
このメッセージ受け渡しのプロセス
And then to shoot
そして撮影へ
New drug to inhibit such a pathway
このような経路を阻害する新薬
It's actually a very important point
実はとても重要なポイントなのです
In terms of acidification
酸性化に関しては
The targeted therapy currently used in hospitals
現在病院で使用されている標的療法
You can see all these proteins
これらすべてのタンパク質を見ることができます
each of these names is protein
これらの名前はそれぞれタンパク質です
These are all membrane proteins of the cell membrane
これらはすべて細胞膜の膜タンパク質です
Some use small molecules to inhibit it
それを阻害するために小分子を使用するものもあります
Some use antibodies to inhibit it
それを阻害するために抗体を使用するものもあります
Let me give you an example
例を挙げてみましょう
For example, the method of liquid drama
例えば、リキッドドラマの手法。
this is lung cancer
これは肺がんです
Lung cancer in the East is very different from lung cancer in the West
東洋の肺がんは西洋の肺がんとは大きく異なります
Lung cancer in the East has a characteristic
東洋の肺がんには特徴がある
early-onset lung cancer in women
女性の若年性肺がん
relatively high
比較的高い
There is another very important feature
もう一つ非常に重要な機能があります
It is the liquid drama method that the protein will have a so-called mutation
いわゆるタンパク質に突然変異を持たせるという液劇手法です
it will have this mutation
この突然変異を持つことになります
The advantage is that once the method of this liquid drama changes
利点は、この液体ドラマの手法が変わると、
Add this medicine outside
この薬を屋外に追加します
This TKI is a drug
このTKIは麻薬です
Now maybe everyone talks about Aretha
今では誰もがアレサについて話しているかもしれません
everyone will understand
誰もが理解するでしょう
This is a targeted therapy drug for cancer
これはがんの標的療法薬です
The advantage is that once there is a mutation
利点は、一度突然変異が発生すると、
These drugs can inhibit their
これらの薬はそれらを阻害する可能性があります
so that it doesn't generate this rep suppression
この繰り返し抑制が発生しないようにするため
But these patients take medicine
しかし、これらの患者は薬を服用しています
After about six months to a year, unfortunately
半年から1年くらい経つと、残念ながら
Almost always produces a second mutation
ほぼ常に 2 番目の突然変異が生成されます
The second mutation of this place
この場所の2番目の突然変異
Bad once mutated
一度変異すると悪い
They eventually develop resistance
彼らは最終的には耐性を獲得します
So it will recur in the end
だから結局再発するんだよ
Then this is still the oriental lung
それなら、これはやはり東洋の肺です
an unsolvable problem
解決不可能な問題
There is still no way
まだ方法はありません
So from this point of view
したがって、この観点からすると
you can understand
あなたは理解できます
protein is a
プロテインは
In fact, it is a very complicated mechanism
実はとても複雑な仕組みなんです
Then we have to understand the whole process well.
次に、プロセス全体をよく理解する必要があります
We can devise new methods and strategies
新しい方法や戦略を考案できる
to understand the process
プロセスを理解するために
The most complicated thing is that it is not a single path
最も複雑なのは、パスが 1 つではないことです
It's called all roads lead to Rome
それは「すべての道はローマに通ず」というものです
In terms of medical cancer law
がん医療法に関して
this is a cell
これは細胞です
It has at least three, four or more
少なくとも3つ、4つ以上ある
different way
違う方法
In other words
言い換えると
Say your cancer is treated today
あなたのがんが今日治療されたと伝えてください
you stuck this road
あなたはこの道に行き詰まった
Today, the Central Plains Court closed this road
今日、中原裁判所はこの道路を閉鎖した
I can also get from Southport
サウスポートからも行けます
from another direction
別の方向から
or from that highway
あるいはその高速道路から
I go shopping in Sogo
そごうに買い物に行きます
there are so many roads
道がたくさんある
So how can these systems
では、これらのシステムはどのようにして実現できるのでしょうか
able to figure out
理解できる
I personally think it is very important
個人的にはとても重要なことだと思っています
Because in traditional protein research
なぜなら、従来のタンパク質研究では
Usually it is to study a Protin
通常、それはタンパク質を研究することです
But it's actually a systemic problem
しかし、それは実際にはシステム的な問題です
Then I use this example
次に、この例を使用します
It's easier to understand when you explain it to everyone
みんなに説明するとわかりやすいよ
I'm here
私はここにいます
Nakahara Institute expects
中原研究所が期待するのは
Each of us should do a good job in research
私たち一人ひとりが研究で良い仕事をすべきです
well done research
よくできた研究
My students, I just take out two of them
生徒たちよ、二人を連れ出すだけだよ
most related to me
私に最も関係のある
In theory, my students should work hard and earnestly.
理論的には、私の生徒たちは一生懸命真剣に取り組むべきです。
But is it actually so?
しかし、本当にそうなのでしょうか？
no
いいえ
because in this study
なぜなら、この研究では
There are so many tools that I can't have
手に入らない道具がたくさんある
so i have to rely on others
だから他人に頼らなければならない
This is Mr. Song Yifei from the Information Office
案内所の宋亦菲です。
ok then this is my friend from japan
はい、これは日本から来た私の友達です
Mr. Yixu Hama, Kyoto University
浜 宜秀 氏（京都大学）
So in fact, I have to do a good job in research
だから実際のところ、私は研究で良い仕事をしなければなりません
can't just look at them
ただ見ることはできない
Then if I want to study lung cancer
肺がんの研究をしたい場合
I did not visit the pier with Principal Yang Panchi
私はヤン・パンチ校長と一緒に桟橋を訪れませんでした
probably not too good
大概也不太OK
Because he knows best what lung cancer is
肺がんとは何かを一番知っているのは彼だから
So this is a very important alliance
つまり、これは非常に重要な同盟です
But if research funding is concerned
しかし、研究資金が心配な場合は、
This is Dean Wen, everyone should know
これはディーン・ウェンです、誰もが知っているはずです
Then the deputy king is here
それから副王がここにいます
So if I tell this next joke to only
だから次のジョークを誰かに言うとしたら
Finally someone understands
やっと誰かが理解してくれた
just if you're going to ask for money
ただお金を要求するつもりなら
No one will ask the dean
誰も学部長に質問しないよ
Because you want your self-esteem not to suffer
自尊心を傷つけたくないから
hope you feel better
気分が良くなるといいですね
Usually we go to the smiling person and ask
通常、私たちは笑顔の人のところに行き、尋ねます
then vice wang
それから副王
Then we will ask the dean for money as a last resort.
そして最後の手段として学部長にお金を要求します。
And of course but so what I'm going to say is
そしてもちろんですが、だから私が言いたいのは、
This is just a working network
これは正常に動作しているネットワークです
In other words, if you are going to ask today
つまり、今日質問する場合は、
Can Chen Yuru do research well at Academia Sinica?
陳有宇は中央研究院でうまく研究できるでしょうか？
It's not my problem
それは私の問題ではありません
It is a very complex network problem
非常に複雑なネットワークの問題です
If you want to ask today
今日聞きたいことがあるなら
I will give another simple example
別の簡単な例を示します
For example, let's say we're getting married
たとえば、私たちが結婚するとしましょう
Then you have a girlfriend, boyfriend
じゃあ君にはガールフレンドがいる、ボーイフレンドがいる
you have to predict
予測しなければなりません
you marry him in the future
あなたは将来彼と結婚します
Will you be happy
幸せになりますか
you absolutely need to know his family
彼の家族を絶対に知る必要がある
right
右
For example, you want to know your mother-in-law
たとえば、義母のことを知りたいとします。
Will it be difficult to get along with?
仲良くなるのは難しいでしょうか？
So this is a
これは
complex network problem
複雑なネットワークの問題
OK, so we think protein
そうですね、プロテインだと思います
with proteosomes
プロテオソームを使った
In fact, only through the proteosome
実際には、プロテオソームを介してのみ
In order to be able to understand more systematically
より体系的に理解できるようにするために
what happened to us
私たちに何が起こったのか
at the molecular level
分子レベルで
The first big obstacle is
最初の大きな壁は、
The protein body is so complex
タンパク質の本体は非常に複雑です
what tools are we going to use for research
研究にはどのようなツールを使用しますか
Let's start with the simplest species
最も単純な種から始めましょう
Even a simple E. coli
単純な大腸菌でも
it has thousands of proteins
何千ものタンパク質が含まれています
Then we estimate human
次に人間を推定します
There are at least 35,000 different
少なくとも 35,000 種類あります
different protein
異なるタンパク質
What tool can be used to do this
これを行うにはどのようなツールを使用できますか
So how do we identify proteins
では、どうやってタンパク質を特定するのか
that identifies proteins in this
この中のタンパク質を識別する
what i call identification
私が識別と呼ぶもの
I put this definition first
この定義を最初に置きます
not that i need to know this
これを知る必要があるわけではありません
i am female
私は女性です
I want the so-called identification is
いわゆる身分証明書が欲しいのですが、
you have to tell me
あなたは私に言わなければなりません
I am Chen Yuru
私はチェン・ユルです
I am not Wang Qihui
私は王奇輝ではありません
I'm not Vice President Wang Yu, etc.
私は王裕副総統などではありません。
This is called identification
これを識別といいます
so as a tool
だからツールとして
how to tell you this
これをどうやって伝えるか
The paper spectrometer is here
紙製分光計はこちら
It's a tool that's over a hundred years old
100年以上前の道具です
that from the earliest atoms in our periodic table
それは周期表の最初の原子からのものです
wait a minute we'll talk
ちょっと待ってください、話しますから
OK, let's talk about this first
OK、まずはこれについて話しましょう
Then this paper spectrometer
それからこの紙製分光計
It's actually a stick
実は棒なんです
It can tell your analyte
分析対象物を知ることができます
How much does it weigh
それはどのくらいの重さん
Its concept is actually very simple
そのコンセプトは実際には非常にシンプルです
Its concept is
そのコンセプトは
When we charge the analyte
分析対象物をチャージするとき
under the action of a power plant or a magnetic field
発電所または磁場の作用下で
the time it arrived at the detector
探知機に到着した時刻
Or the path will be different
それとも道が違うのか
So we can use this way
したがって、このように使用できます
to measure the quality
品質を測定する
the size of this
このサイズ
it's complicated
それは複雑です
i guess i won't explain
説明しないと思うよ
It's a very complex instrument
とても複雑な楽器です
In fact, everyone is very concerned about Zhi Puyi
実際、誰もが志溥儀のことをとても心配しています
It shouldn't feel too strange
あまり奇妙に感じるべきではない
Because the first periodic table
なぜなら最初の周期表は
is the first
最初です
For the first element of the periodic table
周期表の最初の元素の場合
It is measured from the concept of fat
脂肪の概念から測定されます
If you still remember this JJ Thompson
JJ トンプソンのことをまだ覚えているなら
He was the first to discover that
彼はそれを最初に発見した
in this power plant
この発電所で
We'll see a so-called charged one
いわゆる有料のものが登場します
a radiation
一個輻射
In fact, it is a lipo
実はリポなんです
So this is the earliest and earliest Zhipu
つまり、これが最も初期の最初のZhipuです
You can see this atom of Niang
ニアンのこの原子が見えます
it has two parity digits
2 つのパリティ桁があります
20 and 22
20と22
because its weight is different
重さが違うから
So it's under this action of this magnetic field
つまり、この磁場の作用下にあるということです
it deflects
それはそれます
This is a lipo
これはリポです
So using this simple concept
この単純な概念を使用すると、
we can build
私たちは建てることができます
This human this is probably the human always the ultimate
この人間はおそらくいつも最後の人間だ
The most important thing is the periodic table
一番大切なのは周期表です
However, although Zhipu has been
ただし、Zhipu は
so widely used
とても広く使われている
But in the early days
しかし初期の頃は
Actually none of us ever knew
実際のところ、私たちの誰も知りませんでした
He can do biomolecular analysis
彼は生体分子分析ができる
In the development of this whole history, this Zhipu
この歴史全体の発展の中で、この志埔は
from the earliest atoms
最も初期の原子から
then to the chemical age
そして化学時代へ
many, many small molecules
たくさんの小さな分子
until the 1970s
1970年代まで
Polymer oil extraction and so on
ポリマーオイル抽出など
carried on until later
後まで続けられた
what about later
後はどうですか？
around 1995
1995年頃
By Mr. Tanaka from Japan
日本の田中さんより
He's an engineer from Xu Ma's company
彼はXu Maの会社のエンジニアです
Then when he was doing an experiment
それから彼が実験をしていたとき
That era was the age of polymers
あの時代はポリマーの時代だった
So his task is to find a material
したがって、彼の仕事は材料を見つけることです
Let this polymer be our textile
このポリマーを私たちの繊維にしましょう
plastic these
プラスチックこれら
Can be tested with Zhipu
Zhipuでテスト可能
How big is this polymer?
このポリマーの大きさはどれくらいですか?
then he made a mistake once
それから彼は一度間違いを犯した
Accidentally discovered the world's first protein map
世界初のタンパク質地図を偶然発見
Then its method is to use the concept of laser
その方法はレーザーの概念を使用することです
To do the identification of this mass spectrum
この質量スペクトルの同定を行うには
Then there is another professor John Fenn
それからもう一人のジョン・フェン教授がいます
He has always hoped to use high-voltage electricity
彼はいつも高圧電気を使いたいと思っていた
able to make this deepening molecule
この深くなる分子を作ることができます
be able to electrify it to be detected
感電して検出できるようにする
So he's using a method called electrospraying
そこで彼はエレクトロスプレーと呼ばれる方法を使用しています
It's the high voltage that sprays it out
高電圧が噴出するのです
the two of them
その内二人
discovered at almost the same time
ほぼ同時に発見された
for this protein molecule
このタンパク質分子について
capable of mass spectrometry
質量分析が可能
So in 2002 when they
それで2002年に彼らは
Received the Nobel Prize in Chemistry
ノーベル化学賞を受賞
Then this is in this field
それから、これはこの分野にあります
a very important development
非常に重要な進展
Then I'll pick one of the easy ones first.
それでは、最初に簡単な方法から 1 つを選択します
explain to everyone
みんなに説明する
Why can mass spectrometry measure this mass?
なぜ質量分析ではこの質量を測定できるのでしょうか?
this size
このサイズ
Then what I introduce here is
そこで今回紹介するのは、
Mr. Araka's laser mechanism
アラカさんのレーザーメカ
laser assist
レーザーアシスト
Lei Se entrusted oil treatment method
Lei Se委託油処理法
In fact, it has two important elements
実はこれには 2 つの重要な要素があります
The first is called organic matter
1つ目は有機物と呼ばれるものです
This mechanism is some small molecular acids
このメカニズムは、いくつかの低分子酸です。
It is very easy to generate in this light ion
この軽イオンは非常に簡単に生成できます
This light ion can be transferred to
この軽イオンは、
Let it be charged on this analytical sample
この分析サンプルに帯電させます
The second important element is lace
2番目に重要な要素はレースです
The role of this lace is
このレースの役割は
When we mix these analytes with the organic
これらの分析物を有機物と混合すると、
Because lace has energy
レースにはエネルギーがあるから
So when Lei Se went to take this sample
それで、Lei Seがこのサンプルを取りに行ったとき
It will put the organic light ion
有機光イオンを入れます
let it jump out
飛び出させてください
and then separated from the analyte
その後、分析物から分離されます
so make it electrified
だから電化させろよ
when it is electrified
電化されているとき
It actually uses the concept of a race
実際にはレースの概念が使用されています
to measure its size
そのサイズを測るために
Its principle is actually very simple
その原理は実はとてもシンプルです
after lace sparks it
レースが火花を散らした後
Different molecules will get the same potential energy
異なる分子は同じ位置エネルギーを得る
This potential energy is converted into
この位置エネルギーは次のように変換されます。
It's a race in an electric field, a free one out of five
それは電気フィールドでのレース、5 つのうち 1 つが無料です
Then we know that when the potential energy is converted into kinetic energy
次に、位置エネルギーが運動エネルギーに変換されるときがわかります。
Because this speed, this V means that speed is inversely proportional to mass
この速度、この V は速度が質量に反比例することを意味するため、
So a fat person has a slower speed, and a thinner person has a faster speed
つまり、太っている人は速度が遅く、痩せている人は速度が速いです
So when the two of us go for a run
それで二人で走りに行くとき
fast thin people run fast
速い細い人は速く走る
He arrives first and the fat man arrives later
彼が先に到着し、太った男が後に到着する
So take advantage of this different flight time
この異なる飛行時間を活用してください
We can analyze the different quality
さまざまな品質を分析できます
Then this is a very simple principle of Zhipu
これは Zhipu の非常に単純な原則です
Then it will be difficult
それなら難しいだろうね
Please take this matter seriously
この件を真剣に受け止めてください
use weight for this matter
使用重量
Why can I tell you the different identities of these three people
なぜこの 3 人の異なるアイデンティティについてお話しできるのですか
This same one was made by my daughter for me
これと同じものは娘が私のために作ってくれました
I told her I'm looking for three different people
私は彼女に、3人の異なる人を探していると言いました
Then she told me to find these three
それから彼女は私にこの3つを見つけるように言いました
please think about it
考えてみてください
I just mentioned that QP is weighing
QP が計量していると先ほど言いました
right
右
OK, let's look at the weight
はい、重さを見てみましょう
The lady in the shirt is the thinnest one
シャツを着ている女性が一番痩せています
45 kg casually
何気なく45kg
Those two people are a little bit fatter
あの二人はちょっと太ったね
55 kg
55kg
I just weighed the thing
ちょうど物の重さを量ったところです
can i judge
判断してもいいですか
His name is Hushan, his name is Mizushima, his name is Triangle
彼の名前はフーシャン、彼の名前は水島、彼の名前はトライアングル
Everyone thinks no, right?
誰もがノーだと思いますよね？
Then please think again
それからもう一度考えてください
can you think or tell me
考えてもらえますか、教えていただけますか
I can only give you a stick scale
棒秤しかあげられない
How you can use stick scales
スティックスケールの使い方
separate the two
二つを分ける
Think again, everyone, the concept of weighing
みなさん、計量という概念をもう一度考えてみましょう
anyone figured it out
誰かがそれを理解した
In fact, the reason is very simple
実はその理由はとても単純で、
Everyone's body proportions are different
体のプロポーションは人それぞれ違います
For example, Mrs. Mizushima has a super big head
たとえば、水島さんは頭がとても大きいです。
that her legs are a little bit
彼女の足は少しだけだということ
also short
短いのも
then Mrs. Triangle
それから三角夫人
her head is bigger
彼女の頭はもっと大きいです
But look carefully at her hands and feet
でも彼女の手と足をよく見てください
Actually a little thinner
実際はもう少し薄い
if you look carefully
よく見ると
So if I cut them up
それで、もし私がそれらを切り取ったら
If it is divided into four limbs and disassembled completely
四肢に分けて完全に分解すると
The proportion of their body
彼らの体の比率は
the weight of her hands her head her feet
彼女の手の重さ、頭、足の重さ
It's actually different
実際は違います
So if each of you looks very different
だから、もしあなたたち一人一人が全く違って見えるとしたら
I can make this limb very precise
この手足を非常に正確に作ることができます
words of weight
重みのある言葉
Then I can actually learn from this so-called combination
そうすれば、このいわゆる組み合わせから実際に学ぶことができます
To judge that this is water pouring
これを水掛けだと判断するには
this is a triangle
これは三角形です
So you use the concept
それで、あなたはその概念を使用します
You can actually do protein analysis
実際にタンパク質分析ができる
purely by weight
純粋に重量で
Then I will use this concept to explain to you
次に、この概念を使用して説明します
Why weighing can start from weighing
なぜ計量は計量から始められるのか
to tell you what this protein is
このタンパク質が何であるかを説明します
Well, this technique is called protein identification.
さて、この技術はタンパク質同定と呼ばれます。
then we know
そうすればわかります
This protein is made up of 20 common amino acid arrangements
このタンパク質は 20 個の一般的なアミノ酸配列で構成されています
Each amino acid is different because of its structure
それぞれのアミノ酸はその構造が異なるため、
so its weight is completely different
なので重さが全然違います
Then I'm going to measure a protein weight today
じゃあ今日はたんぱく質の重量を測ってみます
If I measure the whole weight, it will be the same as the problem just now
全体の重さを測ったらさっきの問題と同じになる
same weight too much
同じ体重多すぎる
45 kg is too many people
45kgは多すぎる
55 kg is too many people
55kgって人多すぎるよ
I can't really tell who's who.
誰が誰なのか全く分かりません。
But if I cut this protein into pieces
でもこのタンパク質を細かく切ってみたら
Then this cut is of course a regular cut
では、このカットはもちろん通常のカットです
At this time, after the protein is cut into fragments
このとき、タンパク質が断片化された後、
because every fragment
なぜなら、あらゆる断片が
Because this sequence of every protein and amino acid
なぜなら、この配列はあらゆるタンパク質とアミノ酸の配列だからです。
is unique
ユニークです
Everyone's sequence is different
順番は人それぞれ違います
so when i cut
だから私が切ったとき
cut out fragments of this ecology
この生態の断片を切り取る
Its sequence is also unique
その並びも独特です
That's because each amino acid has a different weight
それは各アミノ酸の重さが異なるためです
So this time I can go and put this weight
だから今度はこの体重を乗せることができる
Test this separately
これを個別にテストしてください
side out
サイドアウト
Then if the sequence composition of this protein is different
では、このタンパク質の配列構成が異なるとすると、
The weight of the fragment it produces
生成される破片の重量
Must be a unique set
一意のセットである必要があります
like a fingerprint
指紋のように
everyone is different
誰もが違う
So using the concept
したがって、その概念を使用すると、
I can do the comparison
比較もできるよ
So in this methodology
したがって、この方法論では
We can start with some enzymes
いくつかの酵素から始めましょう
chop protein into pieces
プロテインを細かく刻む
that in this example
それはこの例では
It uses an enzyme called Tripsing
トリプシングと呼ばれる酵素を使用します。
These enzymes must be very specific
これらの酵素は非常に特異的でなければなりません
it will recognize
それは認識するだろう
specific amino acids it will cut
特定のアミノ酸をカットします
so it encounters this red
だからこの赤に出会う
it's just
それはただ
after you cut
切った後
Because the order of the proteins is different
たんぱく質の順番が違うから
So you can think of it as saying
したがって、次のように考えることができます
each protein has its own
それぞれのタンパク質には独自のものがあります
A very unique set of Peptide pieces
非常にユニークなペプチド片のセット
At this time, I will use the mass spectrometer to weigh
このとき、質量分析計を使用して重さを量ります
I'm going to test it
テストしてみます
The weight of this fragment
この破片の重さ
what are they
彼らは何ですか
So I am at this time
だから私はこのとき
You can put this Peptide
このペプチドを入れることができます
this pile of debris
この瓦礫の山
To measure mass spectrometry
質量分析を測定するには
Then this mass spectrum is a snack
そうすると、この質量スペクトルはおやつになります
That means mass means weight
つまり質量とは重さのことです
So this goes from 600 weight to 3000
つまり、ウェイトは 600 から 3000 になります。
Each bar represents the weight of each segment
各バーは各セグメントの重みを表します
Even QP can help you measure all the weight
QP もすべての重量を測定するのに役立ちます
After this quality
このクオリティの後は
I'm going to ask next
次に聞いてみます
In the database we just mentioned
先ほど述べたデータベースでは
DNA produces RNA
DNAはRNAを生成する
So as long as the DNA sequence is determined
DNA配列が決定されている限り
Possibility of producing RNA to produce protein
RNAを生成してタンパク質を生成する可能性
know all
全てを知っている
So I have a large database
それで私は大規模なデータベースを持っています
I skip this first
最初にこれをスキップします
I have a large database
大規模なデータベースを持っています
in this database
このデータベースでは
has the sequence of each protein
各タンパク質の配列を持っています
The sequence of each protein is inside
各タンパク質の配列は内部にあります
So my next step is to ask
そこで私の次のステップはこう尋ねることです
ask the computer
コンピューターに尋ねる
in all your databases
すべてのデータベースで
which protein sequence
どのタンパク質配列ですか
Most likely to produce the quality just now
現時点での品質を生み出す可能性が最も高い
so this time
それで今回は
You need to ask the computer to do the calculation for you
コンピュータに計算を依頼する必要があります
follow your orders
命令に従ってください
Meet this Lizing in red
赤い服を着たリジングに会いましょう
specific amino acid
特定のアミノ酸
it's just
それはただ
it takes every protein
あらゆるタンパク質が必要です
all possible theoretical
あらゆる可能な理論的
Calculate it all for you
すべてあなたに代わって計算します
So after it calculates 30,000 records
30,000 レコードを計算した後
Every data has
あらゆるデータには、
Then you go to pen pair
それからペンペアに行きます
Which protein is closest to the experimental quality
どのタンパク質が実験品質に最も近いか
Then it will tell you at this time
そうすればこの時点で教えてくれます
I know it's the protein
プロテインならわかるけど
So just now I omitted one
それで今一つ省略しました
So in this step three
したがって、このステップ 3 では、
is that you have to take this result you got
この結果を受け入れなければならないということです
Send it to the computer database to do pen pairing
ペンのペアリングを行うためにコンピュータのデータベースに送信します
You tell him how you're going to cut
あなたは彼にどのようにカットするかを伝えます
Do I have some protein?
プロテインはありますか？
For example, we just talked about adding a zero acid
たとえば、先ほどゼロ酸の追加について話しました。
it weighs differently
重さが違う
Was it added or not?
追加されたのか、されなかったのか？
And then it's interesting
そして、それは興味深いです
you have to tell it the database
データベースを伝える必要があります
Like before we try first it used to happen
最初に試す前のように、よくあったことだ
a very funny thing
とても面白いこと
The director of a certain hospital told us
ある病院の院長が言っていました。
This is the patient's sample
これは患者さんのサンプルです
How to test is a mouse
テスト方法はマウスです
It's a mouse
ネズミです
It was later discovered that
後で判明したのは、
that his sample was contaminated
彼のサンプルは汚染されていた
And there was a very serious thing that happened
そしてとても重大な事が起こりました
I have a friend
友達がいます
he is in a core facility
彼は中核施設にいる
Then the detected protein is AIDS protein
すると、検出されたタンパク質はエイズタンパク質です
The HIV virus must be above P3 level
HIV ウイルスは P3 レベル以上でなければなりません
can do
できる
then that
それからそれ
Then it was a coincidence
それからは偶然でした
The Poster that happened to be sent for testing
たまたまテストのために送られてきたポスター
he has no concept
彼には概念がない
He thought that AIDS came from himself
彼はエイズは自分自身から来たものだと思っていた
This time there was no concept of a bitch
今回はビッチという概念がなかった
so he is nervous
だから彼は緊張している
He ran to the hospital for examination
彼は検査のために病院へ走った
His wife also went to check
奥さんも見に行った
Will he get AIDS
彼はエイズにかかるでしょうか
Then of course not
それならもちろんそうではありません
The reason that was finally found out was that
最後に調べなければならない本当の理由は、
that laboratory is contaminated
あの研究室は汚染されている
It's that they take a cell from another lab
それは彼らが別の研究室から細胞を持ち出すということです
Turns out that cell is infected with HIV
細胞がHIVに感染していることが判明
that is an extremely dangerous thing
それは非常に危険なことです
Fortunately later
幸いにも後で
It was my friend who detected this.
これを発見したのは私の友人でした。
AIDS detected
エイズが検出されました
So that lab was wiped out afterward.
そのため、その研究室はその後消滅しました。
So Straight Spectrum Ritual A
ソー・ストレート・スペクトラム・リチュアルA
very sensitive method
非常に繊細な方法
Then we still have a lot of fun experience
まだまだ楽しい経験がたくさんあります
For example, someone wants to make Taiwan's unique fish species
たとえば、台湾固有の魚種を作りたいと考えている人がいるとします。
fish are not genetically present
魚は遺伝的に存在しない
Then you have to find something similar or not as good
次に、似たもの、またはそれほど良くないものを見つける必要があります
to do this analysis
この分析を行うには
ok , so a method like this
さて、このような方法です
because every protein
なぜなら、あらゆるタンパク質が
the quality of the ecology it produces
それが生み出すエコロジーの質
like a fingerprint
指紋のように
So such a method
そこで、そのような方法
protein identification
タンパク質の同定
Then with this method
そこでこの方法で
greatly surpassed our
私たちを大きく上回りました
Protein Analysis Challenges and Limitations
タンパク質分析の課題と限界
In the past, you had to analyze a protein
以前はタンパク質を分析する必要がありました
you have to save it
保存しなければなりません
Then do the analysis
次に分析を行います
One protein could take you two years
プロテイン1つで2年かかることもある
But now you only need one cell
しかし、今必要なのは 1 つのセルだけです
You do paper spectrum analysis for two hours
紙のスペクトル分析を 2 時間行います
you get at least a few hundred
少なくとも数百は得られる
Even the data of thousands of proteins
数千のタンパク質のデータさえも
can know very quickly
とても早く知ることができる
it all depends on
それはすべてにかかっています
The continuous improvement of paper notation technology
紙の記譜技術の継続的な改善
and this analysis technology information technology
そしてこの解析技術・情報技術
This refinement of information software
この情報ソフトの改良
the next question is
次の質問は
we have this technology
私たちはこの技術を持っています
then can we ask a question
それから質問してもいいですか
How many proteins are there in humans
人間にはどれくらいのタンパク質が存在するのか
Can we, as just mentioned
今述べたように、できますか
Human Genetic Project
人類遺伝プロジェクト
Genome's plan is the same
ゲノムの計画も同じだ
Find out all the human protein maps
すべてのヒトタンパク質マップを調べてください
The most crucial question is
最も重要な質問は、
we keep asking
私たちは問い続けます
Actually this is still unanswered
実はこれはまだ未解決なんです
Does each gene produce a corresponding protein?
それぞれの遺伝子は対応するタンパク質を生成しますか?
is this the answer
これが答えですか
not necessarily
必ずしも
How much protein does a human have
人間にはどのくらいのたんぱく質があるのか
have no idea
全く分かりません
There's no way to be 100% sure yet
100%確実なことはまだありません
Of course the more important question
もちろん、より重要な質問は
If we want to be able to treat diseases
病気を治療できるようになりたいなら
Learn more about life functions
生命機能について詳しく学ぶ
we want to find
私たちは見つけたいです
Key molecules in these regulation
これらの規制における重要な分子
to help us understand
私たちの理解を助けるために
even go
行っても
The so-called control of the disease
いわゆる病気のコントロール
even suppress it
それを抑制することさえ
that's important in this
それはこれで重要です
Human Protein is under the project of relative human genome
ヒトタンパク質は相対的なヒトゲノムのプロジェクトの下にあります
There is a very important international organization called
という非常に重要な国際機関があります。
International Protein Organization abbreviated as HuPo
国際タンパク質機関、略称HuPo
Then HuPo in 2012
その後、2012 年に HuPo が登場
They started a huge collaborative project all over the world
彼らは世界中で大規模な共同プロジェクトを開始しました
Then they want to be like the Human Genome Project
そして彼らはヒトゲノム計画のようになりたいと考えています
able to convert every possible protein
あらゆるタンパク質を変換できる
find it all
全部見つけて
This project was developed by several people at that time
このプロジェクトは当時数名で開発されました
Included in Yongki Pack in Korea
韓国のヨンギパックに含まれています
Hankhawk in the United States
アメリカのハンホーク
and Sweden in Europe
そしてヨーロッパのスウェーデン
They co-signed such a plan
彼らはそのような計画に共同署名した
The level of this program is very, very many people participating
このプログラムのレベルは非常に多くの人が参加しています
A total of 25 countries are involved in this chromosome
この染色体には合計 25 か国が関与しています
Chromosome-based Human Proteome Project
染色体ベースのヒトプロテオームプロジェクト
Then why is it called a chromosome
ではなぜ染色体と呼ばれるのか
because it is based on chromosomes
染色体に基づいているので
then you can see
そうすればわかります
That is, we in Taiwan have chromosome 4
つまり、私たち台湾人は4番染色体を持っています。
One reason for picking number 4
4 番を選んだ理由の 1 つは
actually in the early days
実は初期の頃
There are some scholars in Taiwan
台湾にも学者がいる
Especially at Yangming University
特に陽明大学では
when they participated in the Human Genome Project
ヒトゲノム計画に参加したとき
This is dominated by chromosome 4
これは4番染色体が優勢です
And the Alpha-Vetal Protein of liver cancer
そして肝臓がんのα-βタンパク質
Molecules of this liver cancer
この肝臓がんの分子
on chromosome 4
4番染色体上
Then I am happiest that our mainland is here
それなら、私たちの本土がここにあることが一番嬉しいです
In fact, they have been suppressing us
実際、彼らは私たちを抑圧してきたのです
The last agreement we participated in
私たちが参加した最後の協定
in the name of Taiwan
台湾の名において
And they agree that we can fly the flag
そして彼らは私たちが国旗を掲げてもよいことに同意します
it's the thing i'm most proud of
それは私が最も誇りに思っていることです
Then the mainland has also expanded very large in the past few years
そして、本土もここ数年で非常に大きく拡大しました
that he for... you can see
彼は... 見ての通り
He started to choose number 8
彼は8番を選び始めた
Later he picked number 1
その後、彼は1番を選びました
In fact, the smaller the... the smaller the number, the more difficult it is
実は、数字が小さいほど、難しくなります。
because more protein
たんぱく質が増えるので
Do you...know why number 1 was chosen?
あなたは...なぜ1番が選ばれたのか知っていますか?
Because he's gonna do Number 1 and that's it
なぜなら彼はナンバー1をやるつもりだから、それで終わりだから
so they do number 1
だから彼らは1位になる
In fact, they also asked us for help.
実際、彼らも私たちに助けを求めてきました。
we choose number 4
私たちは4番を選びます
Then you can also see like Japan
そうすれば日本も見えますよ
they choose number 3
彼らは3番を選びます
then different countries
それから違う国
like america
アメリカのように
america is here
アメリカはここにあります
America picks No. 17
アメリカは17位を指名
Because the number 17 is the gene of the lung cancer
17という数字は肺がんの遺伝子だから
Important genes are all on number 17
重要な遺伝子はすべて17番にある
Many important cancer genes are also on the 17th
多くの重要ながん遺伝子も 17 日にあります
there is another interesting
他に興味深いものがあります
Iran chooses Y
イランはYを選択
Do you know why?
なぜなのかご存知ですか？
Because the regenerative medicine in Iran is very powerful
イランの再生医療は非常に強力であるため、
They do a lot of that unlucky
彼らはそのような不運なことをたくさんします
So the secret of the skewed body
歪んだ体の秘密
is what they want to know
彼らが知りたいのは
So each country they go to claim
それで彼らが主張するために行くそれぞれの国
different chromosomes
異なる染色体
has a reason for it
それには理由があります
Well, the purpose actually sounds so simple.
そうですね、目的は実際にはとても簡単に思えます。
But it is very difficult directly
でも直接的にはとても難しい
The human genome was drafted in 2004
ヒトゲノムは 2004 年に起草されました
About 20,000 genes
約20,000個の遺伝子
human protein body
人間のタンパク質の体
have no idea
全く分かりません
This is a target we are looking for now
これが私たちが今探しているターゲットです
that in these two years
この2年間で
There has been a lot of importance for this work to emerge
この作品が世に出るには非常に重要なことがあった
That first big job is there in
最初の大きな仕事がそこにあります
He relied on this Pendi professor in the United States
彼は米国のこのペンディ教授を頼りました
he himself is a doctor
彼自身は医者です
A doctor of Indian descent
インド系の医師
Then he uses a very large scale mass spectrometer
次に、彼は非常に大規模な質量分析計を使用します
he is rich
彼は金持ちです
He made an adult organization of 17 people
彼は17人の大人の組織を作りました
6 types of hematopoietic cells
6種類の造血細胞
7 more embryonic tissues
さらに7つの胚組織
because an idea is
なぜならアイデアは
If there are some proteins that have never been present
存在したことのないタンパク質がある場合
No evidence
証拠がない
Could it be because he showed up very early
彼がとても早く現れたからだろうか
then disappeared
それから消えた
So he used massive mass spectrometry
そこで彼は大規模質量分析計を使用しました
to identify proteins
タンパク質を同定するために
Then this article in Nature
次に、Nature のこの記事
this is the first
これが最初です
Articles in Nature
Nature の記事
In total, they identified 17,000 protins
合計で 17,000 個のタンパク質が同定されました
About 84% of all genes
全遺伝子の約84%
Then this article came out at the same time
そして、この記事も同時に出てきました
there is a sebecet
セベセトがあります
Also in Nature
自然の中でも
There is a Professor Kusse in Germany
ドイツにキュッセ教授がいる
then they are scary too
それなら彼らも怖いよ
He probably has a real mass spec
彼はおそらく本物の質量スペックを持っています
do it hard do it hard
頑張れ頑張れ
Then got more than 18000 Protin
18000以上のプロチンを獲得
These two are probably so far
この二人は多分ここまで
A sketch of the largest so-called human protein body
いわゆるヒトの最大のタンパク質体のスケッチ
this is appearing
これは現れています
But after these two jobs
しかし、この2つの仕事の後、
There has been a lot of controversy
多くの論争がありました
The reason is Professor Pendi
理由はペンディ教授
His mass spectrometric identification technique is very imprecise
彼の質量分析による識別技術は非常に不正確です
His statistics are many errors
彼の統計には誤りが多い
So it caused a lot of controversy
それでかなりの物議を醸した
after this job
この仕事の後
but i personally think
でも個人的には思う
Actually this is a beginning
実はこれが始まりなのです
at the same time in sweden
同時期にスウェーデンでも
There is a crazier project
もっとクレイジーなプロジェクトがあります
This is a big project funded by the government
これは政府が資金提供する大規模なプロジェクトです
They take every human protein
彼らはあらゆる人間のタンパク質を摂取します
all antibodies
すべての抗体
As long as the antibody is produced
抗体が作られる限り
he organizes all
彼はすべてを組織します
Regardless of normal tissue, all cancer tissues are stained
正常組織に関係なく、すべてのがん組織が染色されます
he wants to know
彼は知りたいと思っています
human protein
ヒトタンパク質
What is the performance in the whole organ?
オルガン全体のパフォーマンスはどうなっているのでしょうか？
It is a very large project
非常に大規模なプロジェクトです
Then they also published in Size this year
そして今年は『Size』にも掲載されました
Use Tissue
用Tissue
immunostaining
免疫染色
So this is probably
だからこれはおそらく
Come to the biggest break in a job
仕事の最大の休憩に来てください
after this
この後
Many other countries have also emerged
他にもたくさんの国が出てきました
to look for the so-called mesin protein
いわゆるメシンタンパク質を探す
let me explain here
ここで説明させてください
Currently about 15% protein
現在タンパク質は約15％
no evidence
証拠がない
no one knows if they exist
彼らが存在するかどうかは誰も知りません
So everyone's first goal
だから全員の最初の目標は
is to make these proteins
これらのタンパク質を作ることです
Is it possible to find all of them?
全部見つけることはできるでしょうか？
then you can see it's funny
そうすれば面白いことがわかります
strange material
奇妙な素材
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
Because everyone will feel that they have done so much
誰もが自分がたくさんのことをしたと感じるでしょうから
why can't i see
なぜ見えないのか
it must be somewhere weird
どこか変なところがあるはずだ
so you can see
それでわかります
From sperm to pulp
精子から歯髄まで
human beings
人間
Everyone is looking for this mesin protein
誰もがこのメシンプロテインを探しています
On a larger scale is
もっと大きなスケールでは、
166個protein machine
166個プロテインマシン
Of course we in Taiwan cannot lose
もちろん台湾の我々も負けるわけにはいきません
loser does not lose proof
敗者は証拠を失わない
we were in 2012
私たちは2012年にいた
it is through them
それは彼らを通してです
It's not that they agree
彼らが同意しているわけではない
Actually they forced us to say
実際、彼らは私たちにこう言わざるを得ませんでした
Must be Taiwan
台湾だろうな
Because we were helping others to analyze
他の人の分析を手伝っていたからです
then he
そして、彼が
I think you're so good
あなたはとても良いと思います
why don't you claim it
なぜそれを主張しないのですか
So later we passed the Taiwan Proteosome Society
その後、台湾プロテオソーム協会に合格しました
We officially claimed chromosome 4
私たちは4番染色体を正式に主張しました
Then Taiwan is here
じゃあ台湾はここだ
Then the first goal is to put this chromosome 4
そして、最初の目標は、この第 4 染色体を配置することです。
able to figure out
理解できる
I am also very grateful to many schools
たくさんの学校にも感謝しています
Including National Taiwan University, Yang Ming, National Health Institute
国立台湾大学、陽明、国立衛生研究所を含む
There are also high school, City University, etc.
高校や市立大学などもあります。
long root
長根
Every school raises its own money
どの学校も独自に資金を集めています
Let's do this project together
このプロジェクトを一緒にやりましょう
Then one of our arguments is
それでは、私たちの議論の 1 つは、
The argument in Taiwan is
台湾での議論は、
We don't want to go fearless in search of these proteins
これらのタンパク質を恐れることなく探索する必要はありません。
We want to be able to target cancer
がんを標的にできるようにしたい
Because cancer is a common goal of these schools
がんはこれらの学校の共通の目標であるため
So we selected the membrane protein of the cell membrane
そこで細胞膜の膜タンパク質を選択しました。
because i just mentioned
先ほど言ったので
That is, 70% of them use membrane proteins as the target of drugs
つまり、そのうちの70％が膜タンパク質を医薬品の標的として利用しているということです。
So in this project
そこでこのプロジェクトでは
we found an interesting thing
私たちは面白いものを見つけました
membrane protein
膜タンパク質
It is diligently stuck on the membrane of the cell membrane
細胞膜の膜に一生懸命張り付いています
On the cell membrane, it's very crisp and watery
細胞膜の上はとてもシャキシャキしていて水っぽいです
So in fact, the analysis challenge is very big
実際のところ、分析の課題は非常に大きいです
So if the membrane protein of the cell membrane
したがって、細胞膜の膜タンパク質が
It's actually a very lonely area
実はとても寂しい地域なんです
Then we did an analysis
次に分析を行いました
we found out that
私たちはそれを知りました
what is known so far
これまでにわかっていること
Missing protein inside
体内のタンパク質が不足している
about a third
3分の1くらい
all membrane proteins
すべての膜タンパク質
So we decided to say
そこで私たちはこう言うことにしました
We start with the cell membrane
細胞膜から始めます
So this is the latest issue that came out
ということで、これが最新刊が出ました
We combined my lab
私の研究室を統合しました
And Mr. Song Definition
そしてミスター・ソングの定義
And Teacher Yang Panshi
そしてヤン・パンシ先生
Principal Yang Panshi
楊潘石校長
And Alex's professor in the United States
そしてアメリカのアレックスの教授
Together we go to find these membrane proteins
一緒に膜タンパク質を探しに行きます
our thoughts
私たちの思い
Our hypothesis is
私たちの仮説は、
If membrane proteins are important
膜タンパク質が重要なら
Well, let me pick a cancer first.
さて、最初に癌を選択しましょう。
So we analyzed twenty pairs of lung cancer tissues
そこで私たちは20対の肺がん組織を分析しました
Cells from eleven types of lung cancer were analyzed
11種類の肺がんの細胞を分析した
Then we found
それから私たちは見つけました
Actually we should be
実際、私たちはそうあるべきです
The most in this issue
今号で一番多いのは
There are 178
178個あります
Mission protein
ミッションプロテイン
Then you can see these 178 Mission proteins
そうすると、これらの 178 個のミッションタンパク質がわかります。
distributed on different chromosomes
異なる染色体上に分布する
Nine of them are on chromosome 4
そのうち9本は4番染色体上にあります
We found that in fact
実際にそれが分かりました
often have a lot of protection
多くの場合、多くの保護が施されています
Let's say there are 9 new GPCRs
9 つの新しい GPCR があるとします。
This is currently the most important drug target
これは現在最も重要な薬物標的です
In fact we identified that it exists
実際、私たちはそれが存在することを確認しました
We also verify that it exists
存在することも確認します
but what is its function
しかしその機能は何ですか
we welcome the people behind
私たちは後ろの人を歓迎します
able to continue to work it out
取り組み続けることができる
the most important is
最も重要なことは
these are so called jigsaw puzzles
これらはいわゆるジグソーパズルです
These are the so-called analyzes
これらはいわゆる分析です
But what kind of help does it have for medicine?
しかし、それは医療にとってどのような役に立つのでしょうか？
Can we use proteomics
プロテオミクスを使用できますか
Come help us find new targets for cancer detection
がん検出の新しいターゲットの発見にご協力ください
It's a big goal for many
それは多くの人にとって大きな目標です
Let's take an example
例を挙げてみましょう
In this cancer is still a
このがんにはまだ
A disease with the highest fatality rate
致死率が最も高い病気
then if you go to see
じゃあ見に行ったら
You see the top three lung cancer liver cancer
肺がん、肝臓がんのトップ3がわかります
both men and women are the same
男も女も同じだ
Lung cancer is now number one
肺がんは現在第1位です
Then liver cancer came in second
次いで肝臓がんが2位となった
That rectal cancer has been on the rise
直腸がんが増えているということ
third place
第三位
In addition to the so-called detection molecules for liver cancer
いわゆる肝臓がんの検出分子に加えて
And that detector molecule it's not very good
そしてその検出分子はあまり良くありません
There are no molecular tests for lung cancer and colorectal cancer
肺がんと結腸直腸がんに対する分子検査は存在しない
It all depends on the diameter of the large intestine
それはすべて大腸の直径に依存します
or you go to take a picture
または写真を撮りに行きます
You go to analyze this image
この画像を分析してみます
to be able to see
見えるようになる
None of the molecular tests
分子検査は行われていない
So if in summary
要約すると
currently in clinical use
現在臨床で使用されている
These cancer marker proteins are very, very limited
これらのがんマーカータンパク質は非常に限られています
that's all
それで全部です
Many diseases are not tested
多くの病気は検査されていない
so we keep asking
だから私たちは問い続けます
Can we go find new marker proteins
新しいマーカータンパク質を探しに行くことはできますか
So what is a marker protein?
それでは、マーカータンパク質とは何でしょうか?
it means
その意味は
when you are sick or when you have a symptom
病気や症状があるとき
not necessarily sick
必ずしも病気ではない
For example, you can be high
たとえば、ハイになることもできます
when a particular symptom
特定の症状が出たとき
If there is a large increase in protein under this symptom
この症状でタンパク質が大幅に増加した場合
And this large increase is due to the disease
そしてこの大幅な増加は病気によるものです
or its specific
またはその特定の
Then we call this protein a marker protein
このタンパク質をマーカータンパク質と呼びます
Then this marker protein is very, very important
このマーカータンパク質は非常に重要です
you can help the doctor
あなたは医者を助けることができます
For example, some proteins can tell you
たとえば、いくつかのタンパク質は次のことを教えてくれます。
This of the prevention of cardiovascular disease
これは心血管疾患の予防です
marker protein
マーカータンパク質
or like a cancer target
あるいは癌の標的のようなもの
you can test first
最初にテストできます
Does EGFR show
EGFRは表示されますか
Is there a mutation
突然変異はありますか
Only you can eat this shit
このたわごとを食べられるのはあなただけです
Soaring soaring will be effective
急騰急騰が効果的だろう
So if these marker proteins
したがって、これらのマーカータンパク質が
Then we can actually do something like this
次に、実際に次のようなことができます
Can there be more diseases?
さらに病気が増える可能性はありますか
be detected earlier
より早く発見される
especially many diseases
特に多くの病気
still rely on this
まだこれに依存しています
It's the doctor's judgment
医師の判断です
without any molecular detection or even imaging methods
分子検出やイメージング方法さえも必要としない
Are there any successful examples?
成功した例はありますか？
I tell you there are
あると言います
This OVA1 is a software for
このOVA1は、
A kit that loves detection
検出が大好きなキット
is the world's first proteomics
世界初のプロテオミクスです
Developed cancer detection reagents
がん検出試薬の開発
The earliest prototypes were made in the United States
最も初期のプロトタイプは米国で作られました
This Daniel Chien professor at John Hopkins
ジョン・ホプキンス大学のダニエル・チェン教授
what they developed
彼らが開発したもの
Then this research and development in 2009
そして2009年のこの研究開発
They were later transferred to a company
その後、彼らは会社に転勤しました
Then this 2009 officially passed the FDA certification
そして2009年に正式にFDA認証を通過しました。
he can get tested
彼は検査を受けることができる
Then he targets this malignant tumor
そして彼はこの悪性腫瘍を標的にします
The detection rate of malignant ovarian tumors is as high as 96%.
悪性卵巣腫瘍の検出率は96％にも達します。
Then his normal person is
そうすると、彼の普通の人は、
He has a 95% correct rate without problems
問題ありません、彼の正答率は 95% と高いです
so is a very correct
それは非常に正しいです
It is a reagent with high accuracy
精度の高い試薬です
In the traditional detection method of ovarian cancer
従来の卵巣がんの検出方法では
In fact, everyone is currently using the CA125
実際、現在は全員が CA125 を使用しています。
i just mentioned
先ほど言いました
But this Mark is in many, many diseases
しかし、このマークは多くの病気にかかっている
will increase, not necessarily ovarian cancer
卵巣がんは増加するが、必ずしも卵巣がんとは限らない
of course
もちろん
then you can go for an ultrasound
それから超音波検査を受けましょう
But this requires manual judgment
ただし、これには手動の判断が必要です
And when it's sonified
そしてそれが音響化されると
Actually, it's already a big piece.
実はすでに大きな作品なんです。
Unable to do this early detection
この早期発見ができない
So in this Professor Daniel Chuen
このダニエル・チュエン教授では
They just want to be able to use
彼らはただ使えるようになりたいだけなのです
proteomic methods
プロテオミクス法
to find new detections
新しい検出を見つけるために
Then this method is actually
では、この方法は実際には
One of the simplest methods in proteomics
プロテオミクスにおける最も単純な手法の 1 つ
They took the patient
彼らは患者を連れて行った
Take the blood of healthy testers for testing
検査のために健康な検査者の血液を採取する
Fat test stocks
ファットテスト株
So this is a fat stock chart
これは太い株価チャートです
Then every time you see one, it means
そうすると、それを見るたびに、それは、
Oh this is so-and-so protein
ああ、これはまあまあのプロテインです
Then it is more concentrated
そうするとさらに集中力が高まります
the higher its signal
信号が高いほど
Then it is for convenience to analyze
それから、分析するのに便宜的なものです
it puts this high and low
それはこれを高く下げます
transform like this image
この画像のように変形します
The darker the color, the higher the concentration
色が濃いほど濃度が高い
Well then it uses this principle
なるほど、この原理を利用しているのですね
To analyze patients with soft bank cancer
ソフトバンクがん患者を分析するため
patient with health tester
健康検査器を持つ患者
Then everyone can digest for 10 seconds
その後、全員が 10 秒間消化できます
Anyone see anything different?
何か違うものが見えた人はいますか？
It's not easy to see
見るのは簡単ではありません
actually it's pretty awesome
実際、それはかなり素晴らしいです
if i see this result
この結果を見たら
I feel bad
申し訳ありません
look carefully
よく見て
This one over here
こっちだよ
here is a protein
ここにプロテインがあります
is this straightening
これはまっすぐになっていますか
Then the other one is called
次に、もう一方が呼び出されます
Aolipo suggests A1
Aolipo は A1 を提案します
if you look carefully
よく見ると
this place this one
この場所、これ
Projector is a bit unclear
プロジェクターは少しわかりにくい
I use to talk
よく話します
just in
ちょうど入ったところ
The concentration is decreased when the patient
患者が集中力を低下させると、
Then there is actually
それから実はあるんです
This concentration is slightly higher
こちらの濃度は少し高めです
just darker
ただ暗いだけ
you can't see it now
今は見えません
So in this example
したがって、この例では
They found that three proteins
彼らは3つのタンパク質を発見しました
Patients with soft-nest cancer followed healthy testers
軟巣がん患者は健康な検査者を追跡した
Expressed concentration is not the same
表現される濃度は同じではありません
So then put this
それで、これを入れてください
they have another article
彼らは別の記事を持っています
How many articles are there in total
記事は全部で何件ありますか
Then they take this seven proteins
次に、この 7 つのタンパク質を摂取します
Credit to Virvanian
ビルバニアンの功績
This company
この会社
Then this company has these seven proteins
この会社はこれら 7 つのタンパク質を持っています
to do it on a large scale
それを大規模に行うには
It's a clinical test in several medical centers
複数の医療センターでの臨床試験です
Finally, a combination of these five proteins was found
最終的に、これら 5 つのタンパク質の組み合わせが発見されました。
You can do this test of OVA1
OVA1 のこのテストを行うことができます
OK, so after this test is done,
さて、このテストが完了したら、
it can target is
それがターゲットにできるのは
The one before and after the period
期間の前後のもの
it has a different score
それは違うスコアを持っています
it will tell you
それはあなたに教えてくれるでしょう
Your current tumor
現在の腫瘍
Is it a malignant or benign tumor
悪性腫瘍ですか、良性腫瘍ですか
If a benign tumor
良性腫瘍の場合
Back to obstetrics of course
もちろん産科に戻ります
Malignant tumors need to be treated
悪性腫瘍は治療が必要です
After the reagent comes out
試薬が出てきたら
You can see it in 2012 when
2012年にそれを見ることができます
Has reached as high as 10,000 to 20,000 reagents
試薬数は 10,000 ～ 20,000 に達しました
used in the US
米国で使用されている
So this is a successful
それでこれは成功です
This result translated from proteomics
プロテオミクスから翻訳されたこの結果
But here I want to tell you
でもここで言いたいのは
In fact, Professor Daniel Chuen
実際、ダニエル・チュエン教授は、
The one he passed FDA in this kit
彼がこのキットでFDAに合格したもの
when he gave his first speech
彼が最初のスピーチをしたとき
He will tell you as soon as he goes up
彼は上がったらすぐに教えてくれるでしょう
just tell everyone
ただみんなに言ってください
Nine years ago I told you it would work
9年前、私はそれがうまくいくだろうと言いました
In fact, no one believed that he would succeed.
実際、誰も彼が成功するとは信じていませんでした。
The development took nine years
開発には9年かかった
Therefore, when the biotechnology industry has many
したがって、バイオテクノロジー産業が多くの場合、
is a long
長いです
because you have to do a lot
たくさんのことをしなければならないから
a generation of four seasons
四季の世代
From the seven proteins how
7つのタンパク質からどのように
in the beginning from a pile of blood
最初は血の山から
how to pick seven
7つの選び方
How to reduce seven to five
7 を 5 に減らす方法
how to do five
5つをどうするか
then this
それからこれ
It depends on how high or low the concentration is
濃度が高いか低いかによって決まります
Where do you cut to do testing
テストを行うにはどこを切りますか
Then you want every doctor to cooperate with you
それならすべての医師に協力してもらいたい
and multiple medical centers
および複数の医療センター
do it together
一緒にやろう
So this is actually a
これは実際には
very long process
非常に長いプロセス
So we also want
だから私たちも欲しいのです
Please give the hospital more time
病院にもう少し時間をください
We are working hard on research
私たちは研究に熱心に取り組んでいます
Another very important job
もう一つの非常に重要な仕事
was published last year
昨年出版されました
just doing a test
ただテストをしているだけです
National Institutes of Health
国立衛生研究所
Is doing clinical proteomics
臨床プロテオミクスを行っています
teacher in school
学校の先生
That's a scary one too
それも怖いものですね
They are jointly conducted by five research units
5つの研究ユニットが共同で実施
including John Hopkins
ジョン・ホプキンスも含めて
Included in Frey Hutchinson
フレイ・ハッチンソンに収録
a well-known research unit
有名な研究ユニット
an alliance to do together
一緒にやる同盟
they want to ask
彼らは聞きたいのです
Is it possible to learn from the gene body and the protein body
遺伝子本体とタンパク質本体から派生することは可能ですか
combine the two
2つを組み合わせる
Come tell us common sense cancer
常識的な癌を教えてください
Can it be divided into different types
色々な種類に分けられるのでしょうか
that's actually very important
それは実はとても重要なことです
Because common sense grows in the United States
アメリカでは常識が育つから
Then let's look at the genome
それではゲノムを見てみましょう
This picture is a bit complicated
この絵は少し複雑です
but let me explain
でも説明させてください
I only talk about the genetic part
私は遺伝の部分についてのみ話します
in genetic analysis
遺伝子解析では
they are very large
彼らはとても大きいです
Spend a lot of money doing genome analysis
ゲノム解析に多額の資金を投じる
100 people
100個人
You can see that the genes are divided into three large
遺伝子は大きく3つに分かれていることがわかります。
Then this black, yellow and blue
それからこの黒、黄、青
In fact, it is divided into three major
実は大きく3つに分かれます
that big one is
あの大きなものは
I don't want to talk
話したくない
this may be too complicated
これは複雑すぎるかもしれません
three different types
3つの異なるタイプ
But if you look at protein
しかしプロテインを見てみると
This one is protein
これはプロテインです
it can be clearly
それは明らかにできる
Divided into five major
大きく5つに分かれています
Then they later discovered that the five large
その後、彼らは後に、5 つの大きな
Actually there is a district
実は地区があるんです
There is an area of ​​this area of ​​C
Cのこのエリアのエリアがあります
It's so fine, I can't see it
とてもいいです、見えません
It is interesting that the type of C
興味深いのは、C のタイプです。
adipose bowel cancer in the second stage
脂肪腸がん第二期
And what?
そして何？
It's more like that tumor stem cell
それは腫瘍幹細胞に似ています
because many people think
と多くの人が思っているので
Stem cells are responsible for cancer recurrence
幹細胞はがん再発の原因となる
one of the most culprits
最も犯人の一人
So they found out that
そこで彼らは次のことを知りました
C's as long as there are C's this group of people
C のグループが存在する限り、C は
all in the second issue
全部第二期で
Then much like the nature of stem cells
幹細胞の性質とよく似ています
So they judge from this side that
そこで彼らはこちら側から判断した
If it looks like C from this organization
この組織のCっぽいなら
that may require special attention
特別な注意が必要な場合があります
Because of it the patient's recovery
そのおかげで患者は回復した
may not be added
追加できない場合があります
The doctor should do more aggressive treatment
医者はもっと積極的な治療をすべきだ
so from here
だからここから
you can understand that
それは理解できます
Gene sees three types
遺伝子には3つのタイプがある
But the protein sees the five types
でもプロテインは5種類に見える
So you can see in this
これでわかります
each row
各行
Each row represents a protein
各行はタンパク質を表します
every one
みんな
what is it called
それはなんと呼ばれていますか
One is all right, each one represents a patient
一つでいい、それぞれが患者を代表する
so you can see
それでわかります
Then the red, red, blue and blue represent
次に、赤、赤、青、青は次のことを表します。
May be higher or lower in concentration
濃度が高い場合もあれば低い場合もあります
The redder the higher the concentration
赤ければ濃いほど濃度が高い
The bluer is the lower the concentration
青くなるほど濃度が低くなります
So you use this analysis of the protein
このタンパク質の分析を使用します
You can in fact very clearly classify all patients
実際、すべての患者を非常に明確に分類できます。
Divided into five major
大きく5つに分かれています
Then this is for future doctors after surgery
それから、これは手術後の将来の医師のためのものです
He can go to assist the doctor to judge
彼は医師の判断を助けるために行くことができます
Should these people be treated more aggressively afterward?
これらの人々はその後、より積極的に扱われる必要がありますか？
or general treatment
または一般的な治療
that's a lot of work
それは大変な仕事だ
Then we also want to say
それから私たちも言いたいのです
Can we develop some new methods
何か新しい方法を開発できないか
Especially I just mentioned lung cancer in Taiwan and lung cancer in foreign countries
特に、先ほど台湾の肺がんと外国の肺がんについて触れました。
Lung cancer in Asia is very different from lung cancer in the West
アジアの肺がんは西洋の肺がんとは大きく異なります
But if you go to the hospital
でも病院に行ったら
All treatments are imported from the West
すべての治療法は西洋から輸入されています
so I've always wanted to be able to target
だから私は常にターゲットを絞れるようにしたいと思っていました
We are unique to these problems to do this
私たちはこれを行うためにこれらの問題に独自に取り組んでいます
The other one is in this methodology
もう 1 つはこの方法論にあります
Personalized medicine
個別化医療
Definitely the era of the future
間違いなくこれからの時代
So if you want to do personalized medicine
ですから、個別化医療をやりたいのであれば、
Must have personal testing tools
個人用のテストツールが必要
in order to do the corresponding response
対応する応答を行うために
So what we've been developing is
そこで、私たちが開発してきたのは、
Strategies for Personalized Proteome Analysis
パーソナライズされたプロテオーム解析の戦略
This is my personal research interest
これは私の個人的な研究関心です
analysis of the patient
患者の分析
Actually you have a lot of challenges
実は課題がたくさんあるんです
because you have to do enough patients
十分な患者数をこなす必要があるからです
in order to conclude
結論を出すために
So you are above the method
つまり、あなたはメソッドを超えています
you wish it was as simple as possible
できるだけシンプルだったらいいのに
Usually the doctor must take most of the specimens
通常、医師は検体のほとんどを採取しなければなりません
take it for medical treatment
治療のために服用してください
Then only a small part will be given to you
そうすればほんの一部だけがあなたに与えられます
Especially the earlier patients
特に初期の患者さんは
Your samples are getting less and less
サンプルはどんどん少なくなっていきます
So microanalysis is also an important thing
微量分析も重要です
then of course you wish
それならもちろんあなたはそう望みます
can do this analysis very quickly
この分析を非常に迅速に行うことができます
In addition, we think that
さらに、私たちは次のように考えています
In cancer tissue is actually an analysis
がん組織では実際に分析が行われます
cancer marker protein
がんマーカータンパク質
a good material
良い素材
The reason is already large and has been found
原因はすでに大きく、判明しています
This is the blood vessel
これが血管です
Usually the tumor is near the blood vessel
通常、腫瘍は血管の近くにあります
on this tumor
この腫瘍について
Marker protein on this tumor
この腫瘍のマーカータンパク質
Its concentration is usually the highest
その濃度は通常最高です
It is very likely that these proteins
これらのタンパク質が存在する可能性が非常に高いです。
in many ways
いろいろな意味で
Including through the cancer cells will come out
ガン細胞も含めて出てきます
So now many people are testing their blood
だから今、多くの人が血液検査をしている
circulating tumor cells
循環腫瘍細胞
In addition, this cell grinding protein
さらに、この細胞粉砕タンパク質は、
it has a mechanism
それはメカニズムを持っています
It's going to come out with the front end cut off
フロントエンドが切れた状態で出てきます
the last one is
最後のものは
There are many scissor-like enzymes on the tumor
腫瘍にはハサミのような酵素がたくさんある
it cuts these proteins
これらのタンパク質をカットします
So through these three mechanisms
したがって、これら 3 つのメカニズムを通じて
We thought if I could analyze
分析できればと考えました
protein on tumor
腫瘍上のタンパク質
then go to the blood
それから血のところに行きます
I can do so-called non-invasive tests
いわゆる非侵襲的検査を行うことができます
I'm going to do a blood test
血液検査をするつもりです
The most important thing is when you are in the concentration above
最も重要なことは、上記の集中状態にあるときです
The difference in concentration after running down is 1500
走りきった後の濃度差は1500
So in terms of analysis
分析という観点から見ると
In fact, it is relatively easy to analyze this high concentration.
実際、この高濃度を分析するのは比較的簡単です。
this is what we think
これが私たちの考えです
we were a few years ago
私たちは数年前にいました
first developed a
最初に開発したのは
Analytical methods for personalization
パーソナライゼーションのための分析方法
This example is with
この例は
Dr. Chen Jingxun at Changgan Hospital
長安病院のChen Jingxun医師
he is a very good surgeon
彼はとても優秀な外科医です
If you go to see the current colorectal cancer
現在の大腸がんを見に行くなら
All are invasive analysis methods
すべて侵襲的な分析方法です
In fact, there is no such method for molecular detection
実際、そのような分子検出方法は存在しません。
So we analyzed
そこで私たちは分析しました
we developed a
私たちはを開発しました
Very easy way in three steps
3ステップでとても簡単な方法
For each patient, we analyze his cancer tissue
患者ごとにがん組織を分析します
normal tissue near the cancer
がんの近くの正常組織
Because we think people are very different from each other
なぜなら、私たちは人はお互いに大きく異なると考えているからです。
Like the Nature article I just mentioned
先ほど述べた Nature の記事のように
US NCI they only analyze cancer tissue
米国NCIはがん組織のみを分析します
he didn't actually go to see
彼は実際に見に行ったわけではない
Differences between normal tissue and cancer
正常組織とがんの違い
We think people are too different
私たちは人々があまりにも違いすぎると考えています
You are better than people
あなたは人よりも優れています
not too many variables
変数が多すぎない
So what we hope to do is to compare ourselves
そこで私たちがやりたいのは、自分たちを比較することです
It's your own cancer compared to your own normal tissue
それはあなた自身の正常組織と比較したあなた自身のがんです
So everyone just compares themselves
だからみんな自分と比べてばかり
Then we went to analyze this
次にこれを分析してみました
we just kept mentioning
私たちはただ言及し続けました
membrane protein
膜タンパク質
Then we analyzed a total of 28
次に、合計 28 件を分析しました。
patients at different times
さまざまな時間の患者
that in the process
その過程で
In fact, information is a very, very big challenge
実際、情報は非常に大きな課題です
Our fatty skin produces
私たちの脂肪の多い皮膚が生み出すのは、
It could be 100,000 graphs
100,000 グラフになる可能性があります
You can't do the comparison manually
手動で比較することはできません
That's about 7 or 8 years or 4 years in the past
7、8年か4年くらい前の話です
we are very very grateful
私たちはとてもとても感謝しています
at the Central Plains Institute Information Office
セントラルプレーンズ研究所インフォメーションオフィスにて
Teacher Song Deyi and Teacher Xu Wennian
Song Deyi 教師と Xu Wennian 教師
We co-developed a lot of software
多くのソフトウェアを共同開発しました
without their assistance
彼らの助けがなければ
we have no way
私たちには選択の余地がありません
that data is huge
そのデータは膨大です
then advertise
それから宣伝する
That teacher Xu Wennian is the inventor of the natural input method
あの徐文年先生は自然入力法の発明者です
I advertise for him
私は彼のために宣伝します
Please use it more
もっと使ってください
But into the law
しかし法律の中に
But he said he didn't make a dime
でも彼は一銭も稼げなかったと言った
let everyone use
みんなに使ってもらいましょう
ok so in the process
わかりました、それでは進行中です
In this new method
この新しい方法では
The first thing we ask is
私たちが最初に尋ねることは、
Can we measure
測定できますか
already in clinical use
すでに臨床で使用されている
The molecule CEA
CEA 分子
because it means that your method is feasible
それはあなたの方法が実現可能であることを意味するからです
that's good of course
それはもちろん良いです
we can easily detect
簡単に検出できます
then you can see
そうすればわかります
everyone
みんな
If you compare cancer tissue to normal tissue
がん組織を正常組織と比較すると
You go and see this increase in protein concentration
行ってみると、タンパク質濃度が増加しているのがわかります
nearly three times
ほぼ3回
that another patient
別の患者が
about three times
3回くらい
several times
何度か
ok so say
わかりました、そう言ってください
Our strategy idea should be OK
私たちの戦略アイデアは大丈夫​​なはずです
You can easily see it from the organization
組織から見てもわかりやすい
That
それか
Then here you can see
それでは、ここでご覧いただけます
why personalize
なぜパーソナライズするのか
The red dot represents
赤い点は表します
Concentrations in cancer are increased
がんの濃度が上昇する
Click on the big rep for this protein
このタンパク質の大きな担当者をクリックしてください
The more the concentration increases
集中力が高まるほど
ok so you can see
わかりました、それでわかります
In addition to CEA
CEAに加えて
In fact, there is a lot of protein
実はたんぱく質が豊富
is worth doing
やる価値はある
Good but it was a pity for the times
よかったけど時代的には残念だった
A lot of people
多くの人々
If you want to verify the antibody is not acceptable
抗体が受け入れられないことを確認したい場合
Then I think our lab will go back now
それでは、私たちの研究室はすぐに戻ると思います
Let's do it with branch spectrum
ブランチスペクトルでやってみよう
Then if you use the traditional method
次に、従来の方法を使用すると、
The previous method is that the sensitivity is not good enough
以前の方法では感度が十分ではありません
So he has to put all the simplified
したがって、彼はすべての簡略化されたものを入力する必要があります
mix it all up
すべてを混ぜ合わせてください
Then become a group of normal, a group of cancer
それから正常のグループ、癌のグループになります
but sometimes
でも時々
For example, look at this example
たとえば、この例を見てください
If I look at his average
彼の平均を見てみると
This concentration looks high
この濃度は高そうです
You thought it was a good test to do
あなたはそれが良いテストだと思った
Actually wrong
実は間違っている
It is because A is actually the two
それはAが実際に2人だからです
There are two strange patients with particularly high concentrations
特に濃度が高い奇妙な患者が 2 人います
So on average, his concentration is very high
つまり、平均して彼の集中力は非常に高いのです
In fact, just because two people increase
実は二人増えただけで
that a good test
それは良いテストだ
You want most people to be able to increase
ほとんどの人が増加できるようにしたいと考えています
are increased
増加しています
You can single out most of the patients
ほとんどの患者を特定できる
so from here
だからここから
I want to remind everyone that
皆さんに思い出していただきたいのですが、
Design of Experiments in Doing Research
研究を行う際の実験計画
Special consideration must be given to individual differences
個人差には特別な配慮が必要です
actually very big
実はとても大きいんです
Here we are very grateful to Chang Root University
ここに私たちはチャンルート大学に非常に感謝しています
Professor Dechang Zhan and Professor Yu Zhaosong
Dechan Zhan教授とYu Zhaosong教授
They did the back for us
彼らは私たちのためにバックをしてくれました
Method of staining with tissue
組織を使った染色方法
Go find a Stone II protein
Stone II プロテインを探しに行く
Then you can distinguish
そうすれば区別できるよ
Normal Washed Meat and Colorectal Cancer Tissue
正常な洗浄肉と結腸直腸がん組織
Of these 400 patients
この400人の患者のうち
So say this protein
つまりこのタンパク質はこう言えます
yes can do aftercare
はい、アフターケアができます
can go and see how it is
行って様子を見ることができます
Then we also look at its five-year survival rate
次に、5年生存率も調べます。
we found that
私たちはそれを見つけました
If the protein concentration is relatively high
タンパク質濃度が比較的高い場合
This axis is represented by
この軸は次のように表されます。
It's the chance of being alive within five years
その人が5年以内に生きている確率です。
this represents time
これは時間を表します
You can see that the survival rate is relatively low
生存率がかなり低いことがわかります
If the protein concentration is lower
タンパク質濃度が低い場合
higher survival rate
より高い生存率
So representing the concentration of this protein
したがって、このタンパク質の濃度を表すと、
With this patient with colorectal fatty bowel cancer
この大腸脂肪性腸がん患者さんの場合
Can you live a good life?
良い人生を送れますか？
or we say later
あるいは後で言います
is an indicator that may be used
使用できるインジケーターです
Then you can see that the five-year survival rate is high
そうすると5年生存率が高いことが分かります
Only 42% of those with high performance
高いパフォーマンスを持っている人は 42% のみ
If the patient's concentration is relatively low
患者の集中力が比較的低い場合
His survival rate is relatively high, 75%
生存率は比較的高く、75%
The last thing we want to ask is
最後に聞きたいのは、
Can I do a test?
テストをしてもいいですか？
then you can see we don't do a lot
そうすれば、私たちがあまり多くのことをしていないことがわかります
75 patients
患者75名
then you can see in the blood
そうすれば血を見ることができます
this protein exists
このタンパク質は存在します
Then if you use the CEA used in this hospital
そこで当院で使用しているCEAを使用すると
he's really bad
彼は本当に悪いです
early diagnosis
早期診断
Only 14% of him can detect it
彼のうち14%だけがそれを検出できる
But if you add stone2
ただし、stone2 を追加すると
If stone2 can be used to measure 69%
stone2 を使用して 69% を測定できる場合
Then if you put two pits
次に、ピットを 2 つ置くと、
76% can be seen
76%が見える
So from here I think I'll tell you
なのでここからはお伝えしていこうと思います
In fact, proteomics is a
実際、プロテオミクスは、
help you find possible
可能性を見つけるのに役立ちます
A new method for the identification of marker proteins
マーカータンパク質の新しい同定方法
Of course there are still many problems
もちろんまだまだ問題はたくさんありますが、
For example, we just talked about protein concentration
たとえば、先ほどタンパク質濃度について話しました。
protein modification
タンパク質の修飾
include sugar plan
シュガープランを含む
he regulates the immune system
彼は免疫システムを調節する
into the protein
タンパク質の中に
Acidifying it will regulate the transmission of messages
酸性化するとメッセージの伝達が規制される
These are also very important
これらも非常に重要です
to regulate the process of message transmission
メッセージ送信のプロセスを規制する
I just said that
私はちょうどそれを言いました
So we also hope to have a good way
だから私たちも良い方法を見つけたいと思っています
able to take the whole system
システム全体を取得できる
able to identify
識別できる
then we wish to say
それから私たちは言いたいのです
able in the process
プロセス内でできる
to find a molecule in the middle of the messaging
メッセージの途中にある分子を見つける
to develop something like this
このようなものを開発するには
A strategy to block a target of protein acidification
タンパク質の酸性化の標的をブロックする戦略
that's in this part
それはこの部分にあります
We also developed a new method
新しい手法も開発しました
When we say an acidification or a modification
酸性化や修飾というと、
if chemical reaction
化学反応なら
it is known
周知された
We have to go after the chemical reaction
化学反応を追求しなければなりません
what dose it responds to
どのくらいの用量に反応するか
Let's say 400 percent is complete
400パーセント完了したとしましょう
Still 30% deep dance
まだ30％のディープダンス
But in the field of spiritual acidification
しかし、精神的な酸性化の分野では
we discover
私たちは発見します
It seems that everyone doesn't care much about this matter.
この件については、皆さんあまり気にしていないようです。
just ask
ただ聞いてください
Is this protein acidified?
このタンパク質は酸性化されていますか?
it doubles five times
5倍になります
Naling is acidified to the end
ナリンは最後まで酸性化します
Thirty-three percent
33パーセント
one third acidified
3分の1が酸性化
Or are they all acidified?
それとも全部酸性化しているのでしょうか？
In fact, no one has asked this question
実際、この質問をした人は誰もいません
so we last year
それで私たちは去年
No this year
今年はいいえ
We published a new method
新しいメソッドを公開しました
We measure protein phosphorylation
タンパク質のリン酸化を測定します
drug resistance in lung cancer
肺がんにおける薬剤耐性
Is it possible to do something new for this answer
この回答に対して何か新しいことを行うことは可能ですか
So we went to analyze
そこで分析してみました
This drug-resistant lung cancer
この薬剤耐性肺がんは
sorry
ごめん
According to the cells that are sensitive to this Aretha
このアレサに敏感な細胞によると
and lung cancer cells resistant to it
そしてそれに対する耐性を持つ肺がん細胞
we want to ask
私たちが聞きたいのは
What molecules can produce drug resistance
どのような分子が薬剤耐性を引き起こす可能性があるか
then we will analyze
それから分析します
use this method to analyze
この方法を使用して分析します
For the law and CK2
法とCK2を目指して
These two very important ones
この二つはとても大切なものです
well they will acidify
まあ、酸性化するでしょう
then we should say accident
それなら事故と言うべきだろう
this is a bit
これはちょっと
surprised find says
驚いた発見は言う
In this network of protein actions
このタンパク質の作用ネットワークにおいて
We found that these large changes
このような大きな変化があることが分かりました
The red moon represents the time of drug resistance
赤い月は薬剤耐性の時期を表します
Its concentration increases
その集中力が高まります
We found these molecules
私たちはこれらの分子を発見しました
Its change is not due to the concentration of the protein
その変化はタンパク質の濃度によるものではありません
It comes from an increase in protein zero acidification
それはタンパク質のゼロ酸性化の増加に由来します
That is to say, in this control
つまり、このコントロールでは
We found zero acidification changes
酸性化の変化はゼロであることがわかりました
may be more important than changes in concentration
集中力の変化よりも重要かもしれない
I can't show a data today
今日はデータを表示できません
But one of the molecules
しかし、分子の一つが
With the assistance of Yang Panchi and Principal Yang
ヤン・パンチ氏とヤン校長の協力のもと
We found that after kicking out that molecule
その分子を追い出した後、私たちはそれを発見しました
drug resistant cells
薬剤耐性細胞
Cells Reverted to Sensitivity
細胞が感受性に戻った
So I guess it's also proteomics
それもプロテオミクスだと思います
able to tell us
私たちに伝えることができます
Mechanisms of the disease, mechanisms of drug resistance
病気のメカニズム、薬剤耐性のメカニズム
what exactly is it
それは正確に何ですか
and then give it to biologists or chemists
それを生物学者か化学者に渡します
to design a new therapy
新しい治療法を設計する
that last
那最後
I'll talk about it in two or three minutes later.
それについては 2 ～ 3 分後に話します。
In the above, these are more personal research.
上記では、これらはより個人的な研究です。
In fact, everyone in Taiwan has realized that
実際、台湾の誰もが気づいています。
It is very important to deal with cancer and disease
がんや病気に対処することは非常に重要です
So there are some big medical universities in Academia Sinica
中央研究院にはいくつかの大きな医科大学があります
With the efforts of the medical center
医療センターのご尽力により
In fact, there are several very important projects
実際、非常に重要なプロジェクトがいくつかあります
in progress
進行中
First of all, the first one is the Taiwan Human Biology Database
まず、1つ目は台湾ヒューマンバイオロジーデータベースです。
I don't know if you guys have heard of this
皆さんがこれについて聞いたことがあるかどうかはわかりませんが、
Is there? There are many taxis
ありますか？タクシーはたくさんあります
did you notice
気づきましたか
I think it's a big project that I really admire
本当に素晴らしいプロジェクトだと思う
This project actually started from Academia Sinica
実はこのプロジェクトは中央研究院から始まったもので、
to lead to the idea of ​​blood
血の考えにつながる
The idea is to say
アイデアはこう言うことです
If we are going to get to know Taiwanese well
台湾をよく知るなら
generation of disease
病気の発生
Then should we take the samples of the Taiwanese first?
では、まず台湾人のサンプルを採取すべきでしょうか？
Whether it is a patient or a sample from the community
それが患者であっても、地域社会からのサンプルであっても
collect first
最初に集める
and after collecting
そして集めた後
Through our long-term follow-up
長期にわたるフォローアップにより
to understand their clinical development
臨床開発を理解する
and their living habits
そして彼らの生活習慣
health blah blah
健康なんとか
Then put these data
次に、これらのデータを入れます
put these data
これらのデータを入れてください
biochemical reaction with him
彼との生化学反応
make a link
リンクを作成する
to find out the cause of the disease
病気の原因を調べるために
because it involves
関わるからです
very very large quantity
非常に非常に大量の
According to my personal knowledge
私の個人的な知識によると
They are actually legislating
彼らは実際に法整備を行っている
made a lot of effort
たくさんの努力をした
then go talk to the legislature
それから議会に話しに行ってください
talk to the government
政府と話す
It was finally passed in 2012
2012年にようやく可決されました
The plan is actually
その計画は実は
very ambitious plan
非常に野心的な計画
currently run by
現在運営されているのは
Liu Fudong, director of the House Voice Institute
House Voice Institute所長、Liu Fudong氏
And the CEO Shen Zhiyang
そしてCEOの沈志陽氏
Then the main reason is
それでは主な理由は、
hope to understand
理解してほしい
Common Slow Disappearance
一般的なゆっくりとした消失
A relationship between STD genes and the environment
STD遺伝子と環境の関係
Then go to find out the factor of this cure
次に、この治癒の要因を調べに行きます
that's funded by the government
それは政府から資金提供されています
I don't know if I will finish in the future
将来完成するかどうかはわかりません
this is what they told me
これが彼らが私に言ったことです
then if the government goes bankrupt
それで政府が破産したら
I don't know what will happen to this
これはどうなるか分かりません
But now they are working hard
でも今彼らは頑張っている
to carry out such a large project
このような大規模なプロジェクトを実行するには
Then this plan was also received by many
そしてこの企画も多くの方にご好評をいただきました
Echoes from the hospital
病院からのこだま
So at the moment from north to south
それで今のところ北から南へ
There are very, very large hospitals
とても大きな病院がたくさんあります
All medical centers are participating in this program
すべての医療センターがこのプログラムに参加しています
Then this plan is from
それではこの企画は
2012 to 2024
2012年から2024年まで
Then they hope to collect 200,000
その後、彼らは20万ドルを集めたいと考えています
Specimens from the general public and 100,000 patients
一般の人々と10万人の患者からの検体
so everyone here
だからここにいるみんな
If anyone is interested in this
これに興味のある人がいたら
very very hope you will
とてもとてもそう願っています
To be a sample of this people
この人々のサンプルになるために
then they will help you for a long time
そうすれば彼らは長い間あなたを助けてくれるでしょう
Track your health and life
健康と生活を追跡する
And the data of your sample
そしてあなたのサンプルのデータ
so this actually knows something about you
つまり、これは実際にあなたについて何かを知っています
You are also very helpful personally
個人的にも大変お世話になりました
There are branches everywhere from south to north
南から北までいたるところに支店があります
you can go
行ってもいい
tell them you want this sample
このサンプルが欲しいと伝えてください
At the same time, an interesting thing happened
と同時に、面白い事が起こりました
This Leigh-Hawaiers is from 2001
このリー・ハワイーズは 2001 年のものです
Nobel Prize in Physiology
ノーベル生理学賞
Then his important discovery is
そして彼の重要な発見は、
He found a way to control that cell cycle
彼はその細胞周期を制御する方法を発見した
Sale cycle some key elements of this molecule
この分子のいくつかの重要な要素の販売サイクル
Then I think the Nobel Prize-winning team won the prize
だったらノーベル賞受賞チームが受賞したと思うよ
They seem to be starting to think
彼らは考え始めているようだ
It's a social problem, a big problem in the world
それは社会問題、世界の大問題です
So he started to travel around the world
そこで彼は世界中を旅し始めた
He wants to advocate a
彼は次のことを主張したいと考えています
The concept of Bio-Synics
バイオシニクスの概念
This Bio-Synics is like a marker molecule
このBio-Synicsはマーカー分子のようなものです
He thinks that the detection of cancer or disease
彼は、がんや病気の発見が重要であると考えています。
is a very important thing
とても重要なことです
is an important strategy for sustainable health
持続可能な健康のための重要な戦略です
But this requires a lot of effort
しかし、これには大変な努力が必要です
Less able to be done by individual labs
個々の研究室ではできることが少ない
He believes that the power of the state should be
彼は国家権力はこうあるべきだと信じている
Production, government and education work together
生産、政府、教育が連携して取り組む
So he traveled around the world
それで彼は世界中を旅しました
To promote the concept of Bio-Synics
バイオシニクスの概念を推進する
He also came to Taiwan to advocate
彼はまた台湾に来て提唱した
So later under his impetus
その後、彼の勢いで
Washup was opened twice in Academia Sinica and Beijing Medical University
Washupは中央研究院と北京医科大学で2回開設された
Formally established in 2012
2012年に正式に設立
Because the Taiwan divine body biological database just now
だって今台湾神体生物データベース
Specimens have
標本には
So this 2002 Taiwan Barsini School
それで、この2002年の台湾バルシーニ学校
hitch a ride
ヒッチハイク
You can see the five major hospitals in the first issue
創刊号では5つの主要病院がご覧いただけます
The five major projects are all very important diseases in Taiwan
5つの主要プロジェクトはすべて台湾にとって非常に重要な病気です
This leader is all this doctor
このリーダーはまさに医者です
Expanded to 13 projects in 2013
2013年には13プロジェクトに拡大
Then I know there are 14 projects now
すると、現在 14 個のプロジェクトがあることがわかります
This project is actually related to the Taiwan Human Biology Database
このプロジェクトは、実際には台湾のヒューマンバイオロジーデータベースに関連しています。
are complementary
補完的です
Hoping to develop marker molecules for disease
病気のマーカー分子の開発に期待
for this important goal
この重要な目標のために
From this place, I also deeply feel that
私もこの場からしみじみ思うのですが、
In fact, most of these projects are medical teams
実際、これらのプロジェクトのほとんどは医療チームです
But what is lacking is
しかし、足りないものは、
Platforms for these high performance analytics
これらの高性能分析のためのプラットフォーム
Analytical talent
分析の才能
In fact, under this plan
実はこの計画のもとでは、
i think we can go
行けると思います
contribute our technology
私たちの技術に貢献してください
so i personally think
だから私は個人的に思う
in Taiwan
台湾で
I'm glad we have
嬉しいです
The Human Biodatabase
ヒトバイオデータベース
With this Taiwanese Balsney
この台湾バルスニーとは
Our two projects can work together
私たちの 2 つのプロジェクトは連携可能です
then we hope the future
それから私たちは未来を望みます
this is my personal expectation
これは私の個人的な期待です
I always feel
いつも感じています
Many phenomena in the so-called life sciences
いわゆる生命科学における多くの現象
In fact, many times
実際、何度も
we are a descriptive phenomenon
私たちは記述的な現象です
But from a chemical point of view
しかし化学的な観点から見ると
I think many things should be
多くのことがそうあるべきだと思う
countable
数えられる
can put this molecule
この分子を置くことができます
get out one by one
一人ずつ出ていく
so i hope
だから私は願っています
will be able to
ことができるようになります
for these important diseases
これらの重要な病気に対して
we can
我々はできる
not only me
私だけではありません
Everyone together
みんな一緒に
able to convert this protein
このタンパク質を変換できる
how to do messaging
メッセージングのやり方
able to do a digital
デジタルができる
of course
もちろん
there are many things that are
ということがたくさんあります
can do
できる
we hope
望みでは
Currently, except for this plan
現在、このプラン以外では
Academician Cai Mingdao of Zhongyuan Academy
中原学院の蔡明道士
Under the leadership of Academician Wang Huijun
学者の王恵軍氏の指導の下
There is also a Taiwanese protein project
台湾プロテインプロジェクトもある
I am personally responsible for the part of the protein body
私は個人的にプロテインボディの部分に責任を持っています
We hope that with these large integrations
これらの大規模な統合により、
collaboration with physicians with biologists
医師と生物学者との協力
with chemists and statisticians
化学者や統計学者と一緒に
Integration of Informatics
情報学の統合
We want to be able to target diseases that are specific to Taiwan
台湾特有の病気もターゲットにしたい
like i just mentioned
先ほど述べたように
Taiwan-specific lung cancer, breast cancer, and colon cancer
台湾特有の肺がん、乳がん、結腸がん
these three diseases
この３つの病気
We hope to be able to build
構築できることを願っています
the protein web database
プロテインウェブデータベース
Once established
確立したら
our promise is
私たちの約束は
We will put all the information
あらゆる情報を載せていきます
All are open to everyone
すべては誰にでも開かれています
Then we hope that for Taiwan these
そして、台湾にとってこれらが実現することを願っています。
cancer development and treatment
がんの発生と治療
can provide more information
より多くの情報を提供できる
Let the people behind be able to do the testing
後ろにいる人がテストできるようにする
or drug development
あるいは新薬開発
But I still emphasize
しかし、私はまだ強調しています
it takes a long time
時間がかかる
I hope you have some patience
もう少し辛抱していただければ幸いです
what i am most interested in
私が最も興味があること
I am in chemistry
私は化学を専攻しています
Many of my colleagues are experts in drug development
私の同僚の多くは医薬品開発の専門家です
So we also hope that after this network comes out,
したがって、このネットワークが登場した後は、
We were able to find new drug target proteins
新しい創薬標的タンパク質を発見できた
to overcome the lung cancer we were talking about
私たちが話していた肺がんを克服するために
have a lot of questions
たくさんの質問があります
The woman with the mutation and no mutation
突然変異のある女性と突然変異のない女性
No targeted therapy blah blah blah
標的療法はありません
There is also the issue of drug resistance
薬剤耐性の問題もある
In the end, I thank many, many friends
最後に、たくさんの友達に感謝します
It's the kind of research that requires a lot of fields
多くの分野を必要とする研究です
Therefore, we have four cooperation partners at Photobiological Information
したがって、Photobiological Informationには4つの協力パートナーがいます。
There are also foreign countries that I haven't listed yet.
まだ挙げていない海外もあります。
we have many friends who are doctors
私たちには医者の友人がたくさんいます
There are also many SaleBioL bureaus and syntheses
SaleBioL 局や合成局も多数あります
Of course, the most important thing is that I want to thank my many students
もちろん、最も重要なことは、多くの生徒たちに感謝したいということです
I haven't had time to put many of my new student photos in there yet.
新入生の写真をたくさん入れる時間がありませんでした
we're working hard on this
私たちはこれに一生懸命取り組んでいます
We also hope to have some results in the future
今後も何らかの成果を期待しています
Last but not least, I think you can see
最後になりますが、ご覧いただければわかると思います
this is a cell
これは細胞です
I think in this field
この分野ではそう思います
it's actually very interesting very very interesting
実際とても興味深いですとてもとても興味深いです
Although it is an extremely complex world
非常に複雑な世界ではありますが、
then we also hope
それなら私たちも願っています
If any student is interested in this field
この分野に興味のある学生がいれば
You are welcome to explore this field together
一緒にこの分野を探索してみませんか
then i think i'll stop here today
それでは今日はここでやめておこうと思います
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
I think everyone is really feasting on knowledge today
今日は誰もが本当に知識を楽しんでいると思います
Then we start with the most basic scientific research
次に、最も基本的な科学研究から始めます
From Dr. Chen's scientific research
チェン博士の科学研究から
The reason of your own illness and so on
ご自身の病気の理由など
i believe there is
私はあると信じています
do you want to take a break or
休みたいですか、それとも
so far so good
ここまでは順調ですね
If there is a problem or what can I ask you
問題がある場合、または何を質問すればよいですか
please
お願いします
that
それか
so wonderful
とても素晴らしい
I want to ask the teacher
先生に聞きたいのですが
because now it's all about triggering
今はトリガーがすべてだから
I heard that Alzheimer's is caused by the protein in the brain
アルツハイマー病の原因は脳のタンパク質だと聞きました
It seems like our paste
私たちのペーストのようです
Do you ask the teacher to say
先生に言ってもらいますか？
accumulation
堆積
Please explain to the teacher
先生に説明してください
That's one big reason why Alzheimer's is happening.
それがアルツハイマー病が起こる大きな理由の一つです。
It's the protein structure that changes
変化するのはタンパク質の構造です
The protein after that change
変更後のプロテインは、
They should have been there one by one.
彼らは一人ずつそこにいたはずです。
that's because it changes
それは変化するからです
so it all piles up
だからすべてが積み重なる
Yes, this is the reason everyone knows
はい、これが誰もが知っている理由です
I know there are quite a few people
かなりの人がいるのはわかっています
including one of my colleagues
私の同僚の一人も含めて
that new method that they hope to develop
彼らが開発したいと考えているその新しい方法
able to make this process
このプロセスを実行できる
able to make it reply
返信させることができる
no more piles
もう山はありません
good
良い
ask the professor
教授に聞く
That one just mentioned the protein concentration
あれはタンパク質濃度について言及したばかりです
high words
高尚な言葉
the survival rate is relatively low
生存率は比較的低い
Then ask the professor what to do with that
じゃあどうするか教授に聞いてください
just say yes
はいと言って
Does this have anything to do with what you eat?
これはあなたが食べるものと何か関係がありますか？
can reduce protein concentration
タンパク質濃度を下げることができます
The second question is
2番目の質問は、
DNA will
DNA意志
DNA mutations create abnormalities in proteins
DNAの突然変異はタンパク質に異常を引き起こす
then please tell me that
それならそれを教えてください
under what circumstances
どのような状況で
or what causes DNA mutations
または DNA 突然変異の原因
Thanks
ありがとう
Let me talk about the second question first
まず 2 番目の質問について話しましょう
Many of the gene mutations come from genetics
遺伝子変異の多くは遺伝学に起因する
For example, Mediterranean flat snow
たとえば、地中海の平らな雪
It may be more frequent on Hakka women
客家の女性に多いかもしれない
like EGF
像EGF
I just talked about the mutation of the gene in lung cancer
先ほど肺がんにおける遺伝子の変異についてお話しました。
Actually we don't know why
実際のところ、その理由はわかりません
But the oriental mutation
しかし東洋の突然変異
For patients, the mutation rate is as high as 60%
患者の場合、変異率は60％にも達する
But Westerners probably only have less than 20%
しかし、西洋人はおそらく 20% 未満しか持っていません
20%
２０％
so a big difference
とても大きな違いです
This should be three times worse than race
これは人種よりも3倍悪いはずです
The difference between 20 and 60
20と60の違い
So it's probably a genetic issue
じゃあ遺伝の問題かもね
As for what to eat for protein
たんぱく質を摂取するには何を食べればよいかというと、
I'm really not an expert on this
私は実際にはこれについて専門家ではありません
But actually I really don't know
でも実際のところはよくわからない
famous, does anyone know
有名です、誰か知っていますか
I think as far as I know it's a lot of times
私の知る限りでは何度もあると思います
protein changes
タンパク質の変化
In fact, except you don't eat anything
実際、何も食べないことを除けば
In many cases, the influence of the environment
多くの場合、環境の影響で
For example, stress can also cause
たとえば、ストレスによっても引き起こされる可能性があります。
Your overall physical condition, what is your metabolism?
あなたの全体的な体調、代謝はどうですか？
that all affect each other
すべてが互いに影響し合うこと
So I think it should be to maintain a healthy life schedule
ですから、健康的な生活スケジュールを維持することが大切だと思います
this should be the most important
これが最も重要であるはずです
Then what to eat? I really don’t know if there is any participation here.
じゃあ何を食べるかというと、参加者がいるのかどうかはよくわかりません。
that doesn't move
それは動かない
will definitely
間違いなく
how can you do this
どうやってこれができますか
I already understand
もう理解しました
Like I know Ah Fa Petal Protein
ご存知のように、Ah Fa Petal Protein
It should have nothing to do with this
これとは何の関係もないはずだ
What happened when I just arrived is often like drinking
到着したばかりのときに起こったことは、よく酒のようなものです
just have some living habits
ただ生活習慣を身につけるだけで
Smoking increases lung cancer risk
喫煙は肺がんのリスクを高める
already know
もう知っている
some of that may not be very clear
その一部はあまり明確ではないかもしれません
That seems to be related to drinking
それは飲酒と関係があるようです
And it has nothing to do with your staying up late.
そして、それは夜更かしとは何の関係もありません。
Yeah, so I think it should generally be
そうですね、一般的にはそうあるべきだと思います
or a healthy lifestyle
または健康的なライフスタイル
Exercise is of course one of them.
もちろん運動もその一つです。
Thank you teacher for your wonderful speech
先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
What I want to ask is that the teacher just mentioned
私がお聞きしたいのは、先ほど先生がおっしゃいました。
Your lab has special
あなたの研究室には特別なものがあります
to notice
知らせる
for relation
関係のために
leaching acidification ratio
浸出酸性化率
In fact, it has a very significant impact
実は、非常に大きな影響を及ぼしているのです
But the few slides in front of you
でも、目の前にあるいくつかのスライドは
already told us all
すでに私たち全員に話しました
transfection followed by protein modification
トランスフェクションとその後のタンパク質修飾
are very important parts
とても重要な部分です
It was also mentioned later when talking about straight floating.
後述のストレートフローティングの話でも出てきました。
You can choose whether there is acidification or saccharification
酸性化か糖化かの選択が可能
So it seems that leaching acidification with or without
したがって、酸性化の有無に関係なく浸出が起こるようです
for your shower or other
シャワーなどに
Researchers around the world should be well aware
世界中の研究者はよく知っておくべきだ
don't know why they would
なぜ彼らがそうするのか分かりません
didn't notice this
これに気付かなかった
And you and your lab will
そして、あなたとあなたの研究室は、
Why is there a way to notice this
なぜこれに気づく方法があるのですか
Then where is the key
では鍵はどこにあるのか
The other one is also what I told you today.
もう一つも今日お話したことです。
The key is to say
重要なのは、こう言うことです
You work with doctors in other fields
他分野の医師と連携している
We also work with computer experts
コンピューターの専門家とも協力しています
May I ask you to cooperate
ご協力をお願いしてもよろしいでしょうか
How can there be a way to cooperate
どうしたら協力できる方法があるでしょうか
Can you pay attention to what important generosity
どのような重要な寛大さに注意を払うことができますか
Thanks
ありがとう
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
your first question
あなたの最初の質問
very important and crucial
非常に重要で重要な
should mean
意味するはずです
That is to say, people in the field of protein geology
つまり、タンパク質地質学の分野の人たちです。
When analyzing protein zero acidification
タンパク質ゼロ酸性化を分析する場合
Because it is the inner segment Peptide with zero acidification
酸性化ゼロのインナーセグメントペプチドだから
or Protin to extract it
またはそれを抽出するプロテイン
So we're doing proteomic analysis
そこで私たちはプロテオーム解析を行っています
Often we just like to compare
多くの場合、私たちは単に比較したいだけです
sick or not
病気かどうか
or whether there is stimulation or no stimulation
あるいは刺激があるかないか
So everyone is comparing
だからみんな比べてるんだよ
Triple or Triple
トリプルまたはトリプル
but we only know
しかし、私たちだけが知っています
Altogether tripled
合計で3倍になります
You don't know this twice because
あなたはこれを二度知らないので、
Possibly increased protein concentration
タンパク質濃度が上昇した可能性がある
so you double
だからあなたは2倍になります
However, the degree of zero acidification remains the same
ただし、酸性化ゼロの程度は変わりません。
It is also possible that the protein concentration does not change
タンパク質濃度が変わらない可能性もある
But zero acidification triples
しかし酸性化ゼロは3倍になる
Before our method
私たちの方法の前に
Everyone doesn't make a difference
誰もが違いを生まない
Then we thought of a way
そこで私たちはある方法を考えました
Let's change the concentration
濃度を変えてみよう
with protein changes
タンパク質の変化を伴う
we can see at the same time
私たちは同時に見ることができます
we just stumbled upon
私たちはたまたま見つけたばかりです
I'm also surprised
私もかなり驚いています
because I always feel
いつも感じているから
Changes in protein concentration
タンパク質濃度の変化
should be more important
もっと重要であるべきです
in that experiment
その実験で
we discover
私たちは発見します
Those proteins have not changed
それらのタンパク質は変わっていない
fantastic
素晴らしい
As for the second question
2番目の質問に関しては
good question
良い質問
I tell my own experience
私自身の経験を話します
Because I am a very casual person
私はとてもカジュアルな人間なので、
Then I usually run into problems
そうすると、たいてい問題に遭遇します
I will solve it
解決してみます
Then why did you start cooperating with the news?
ではなぜ報道に協力するようになったのでしょうか？
because in the early
なぜなら初期の頃は
When we first analyze
初めて分析するとき
Computers were not good at that time
当時はパソコンがあまり良くなかったので、
So we're gonna make protein firm
タンパク質をしっかりと作りましょう
To send data to the Internet
インターネットにデータを送信するには
send it to the internet
インターネットに送信してください
I don't know can't keep sending and sending
送信を続けられないのかわかりません
The website that was sent later
後日送られてきたサイト
think we're hackers
私たちがハッカーだと思う
They obviously did not notify the network administrator of our Chemical Institute
彼らは明らかに私たちの化学研究所のネットワーク管理者に通知しませんでした
said to take us
私たちを連れて行ってくれと言った
is the one that won't let us use
それは私たちに使わせないものです
say we are hackers
私たちはハッカーだと言う
Then I thought it was serious
そしたら大変だと思った
can't go on like this
このままではいけない
Then I happened to meet at Academia Sinica
そんな時、偶然中央研究院で出会いました。
I met a middle school classmate from my elementary school in the parking lot
駐車場で小学校の中学の同級生に会った
He happened to be in teacher Xu Wennian's doctoral class
彼はたまたま徐文年先生の博士課程のクラスにいた
Postdoc
ポスドク
Then I asked him
それから私は彼に尋ねました
I was recently lodged by that Brock from NCBI
私は最近、NCBI のブロックに宿泊されました。
Could you please write a small program
小さなプログラムを書いていただけませんか
So we usually cooperate in the midst of the problem
だから私たちは問題の最中でも協力することが多い
But there is a very important key
でもそこにはとても重要な鍵がある
You must be able to understand his language
あなたは彼の言語を理解できる必要があります
You can't talk to a doctor to learn a language
医師と話して言語を学ぶことはできない
he can't understand
彼は理解できない
you have to speak his language
あなたは彼の言語を話さなければなりません
it takes time
時間がかかる
Then how about counting the results
じゃあ結果を数えてみたらどうだろう
That is to say like we...
つまり私たちと同じように…
Excuse me
すみません
That is, I think a good cooperation is to
つまり、良い協力とは、
special...
非常的...
open minded
考え方が柔軟な
For example, information paper
たとえば、情報紙
It's a very real problem
それは本当の問題です
It's who does the communication
コミュニケーションを行うのは誰ですか
I usually don't hang up
普段は電話を切らない
even if i help write
たとえ私が執筆を手伝ったとしても
Because this is their credit
これは彼らの功績だから
Then I think everyone should be able to share
それならみんなで共有できるはずだと思います
Common results
一般的な結果
this is very important
これはとても重要です
What's more, you need to communicate frequently
さらに、頻繁にコミュニケーションを取る必要がある
Then I have a very lively personality
それから私はとても活発な性格をしています
So I like to talk to people
だから人と話すのが好きです
Yes, and my students are also important.
はい、そして私の生徒も重要です。
That is, my students are willing to work with them
つまり、私の生徒たちは喜んで一緒に働きたいと思っています
that medicine you must
あなたがしなければならないその薬
is what I said must
それは私が言ったことです
because doctors are busy
医者は忙しいから
They have free time to chat with you over there
向こうではあなたとチャットする自由時間があります
so you must know his language very well
だからあなたは彼の言語をよく知っているはずです
Then you have to be able to say the same thing as him
だったらあなたも彼と同じことを言えるようにならなければなりません
he will do it with you
彼はあなたと一緒にやります
I don't think it's that difficult
そんなに難しいことではないと思います
But you just have to be willing to take the time to
しかし、あなたはただ時間をかけて喜んで取り組む必要があります
It will be fine after a long time
久しぶりに元気になるよ
Because when I went to the hospital of traditional Chinese medicine, actually
というのは、実は漢方病院に行ったときに、
I have never heard of an amino acid
アミノ酸なんて聞いたことない
my students know
私の生徒たちは知っています
Poetin protein heard
ポエチンプロテイン聞いた
But I don’t know Poetin means protein
でも、ポエティンがタンパク質を意味するのかは知りません
But because the life sciences of Zhongyuan Institute are too strong
しかし、中原研究所の生命科学が強すぎるため、
So after a long time, I learned like this
久しぶりにこんなことを学びました
Teacher thank you for your wonderful speech
先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとう
I have a question for your last mention of BioBank
BioBank についての最後の言及について質問があります。
I think BioBank is a very Promise project
BioBank は非常に有望なプロジェクトだと思います
Because Chronic disease is a headache for everyone
慢性疾患は誰にとっても頭痛の種だから
And the problem of global aging that we are now facing
そして私たちが現在直面している世界的な高齢化の問題
Whether it is a developing country or a developing country
発展途上国であろうと発展途上国であろうと
Aging is a serious problem
高齢化は深刻な問題です
And then it's very relevant to chronic diseases
そしてそれは慢性疾患と非常に関係があります
So BioBank
だからバイオバンク
I think it's pretty good that we developed this
これを開発したのはかなり良いと思います
For the future of Taiwan, whether it is the development of the biotechnology industry
台湾の未来のために、バイオテクノロジー産業の発展のために
Or academic development is very good
あるいは学業の発展が非常に良い
But teacher, you also mentioned earlier
でも先生、先ほどもおっしゃいましたね
The concept of BioBank comes from BioSignature
BioBank の概念は BioSignature から来ています
No, because BioBank can first
いいえ、BioBank が最初にできるからです
OK, that's because in short my question is BioSignature
OK、それは要するに私の質問が BioSignature だからです
It is still being promoted
まだまだ推進中です
What about our so-called global competitors?
いわゆる世界的な競争相手はどうでしょうか？
or who the partner is
またはパートナーは誰ですか
is someone
誰かです
Where are similar things being done
似たようなことはどこで行われていますか
Because like our national fitness database
なぜなら、全国的なフィットネスデータベースと同じように、
Actually a good Ball Bank too
実はボールバンクとしても優れています
But this is what we are
しかし、これが私たちなのです
Another good opportunity from the opening
開幕からまた好機
But who else is our competitor?
しかし、私たちの競争相手は他に誰でしょうか?
not to compete now
今は競争しないでください
You know that the era of globalization is called cooperation
グローバリゼーションの時代は協力と呼ばれることを知っていますか
I'll give an example
例を挙げます
Like we do that cancer tissue thing
私たちが癌組織のことをやっているのと同じように
We are cooperating with NCI in the United States
米国NCIと協力しています
Why
なぜ
Because our lung cancer is a mutation of EGA
私たちの肺がんはEGAの突然変異だから
Their lung cancer is a mutation of Carousal
彼らの肺がんはカルーサルの突然変異である
The two sides happen to be the control group
双方がたまたま対照グループである
so we cooperate
だから私たちは協力します
So now at least I have a lot of experience
だから今は少なくともたくさんの経験がある
Even though the mainland has been suppressing us
本土が我々を抑圧しているにもかかわらず
But in fact they still put us
しかし実際には、彼らはまだ私たちを置きます
as a partner
パートナーとして
I'm still the same
私は今も同じです
because you are young
あなたは若いから
i still want to talk
まだ話したい
Of course, Taiwan's resources
もちろん台湾の資源も
with foreign superpowers
外国の超大国と
Support to the mainland
本土への支援
is very rich
とても裕福です
But if you open your heart a little
でも少しだけ心を開いてみれば
you befriend them
あなたは彼らと友達になります
they'll treat you like a friend
彼らはあなたを友達のように扱ってくれるでしょう
So I think cooperation is the way of the future
だから私は協力こそが未来の道だと思う
that's like competition
それは競争のようなものです
like felay i don't think we have any competition
フェレイと同じように、私たちには競争相手がいないと思う
Taiwan is doing very well
台湾はよくやってるよ
that Ganglai's words
ガンライの言葉
I'm afraid there will be some competition
競争が起こりそうで怖い
Because the mainland is Ganglai for them
彼らにとって本土はガンライだから
biggest biggest goal
最大最大の目標
But Taiwan has Taiwan's advantages
しかし台湾には台湾の利点がある
Yes, I think in Taiwan
はい、台湾だと思います
we just go
私たちはただ行くだけです
I feel like I'm going to be a little girl
小さな女の子になれる気がする
so i don't just do that
だから私はそれだけはしません
It doesn't take a lot of resources
多くのリソースを必要としません
Of course I still need some resources
もちろんまだリソースが必要です
I want to talk to Deputy Wang
王副官と話がしたいです
But you can't use that
でもそれは使えない
Why did Zhifu fight with them when buying ingredients?
なぜZhifuは食材を買うときに彼らと争ったのですか？
the impossible
不可能
The mainland buys 100 units at a time
本土は一度に 100 ユニットを購入します
how do you fight him
彼とどうやって戦うの？
he is an institute
彼は研究所です
then i'm just a person
それなら私はただの人です
you can't fight him
あなたは彼と戦うことはできません
So what you have to do is
それで、あなたがしなければならないことは、
Taiwan has an advantage
台湾が有利
So why do we do Philae and Breast Cancer?
では、なぜフィラエと乳がんを行うのでしょうか?
In fact, it was discussed with the court
実際に裁判所でも議論されました
Because we have breast cancer in Philae
フィラエには乳がんがあるから
there are many
沢山あります
powerful expert
強力な専門家
Shen Zhiyang's own breast cancer is doing very well
沈志陽さん自身の乳がんは順調に回復している
And Vice President Chen Jianren is also
そして副総統の陳建仁も
What about lung cancer
肺がんについてはどうですか
Principal Yang Panshi should be at the top of the world
ヤン・パンシ校長は世界のトップに立つべきだ
so i think this
だから私はこう思います
You just have to take advantage of Taiwan
台湾を活かすしかない
don't worry about competition
競争のことは心配しないでください
The problem with competition is
競争の問題点は、
We students and our own time should be faster
私たち学生も私たち自身の時間ももっと速くなるはずです
so
それで
Yes, hear no students behind
はい、後ろに生徒がいない音が聞こえます
Teacher, what do you mean
先生、どういう意味ですか
Like our Bao Bank
私たちの宝銀行のように
we are not alone
私たちは一人ではありません
is to focus on chronic patients
慢性患者に焦点を当てることです
I'm also special
私も特別です
Focus more on lung cancer and breast cancer
肺がんと乳がんにさらに重点を置く
Actually I didn't let it go
実は手放さなかった
But if you want to see there is
でも見たいならあるよ
Actually quite sick
実はかなりの病気
i took it off
私はそれを脱ぎました
just a lot of sickness
ただ病気が多いだけ
many cancers have
多くの癌は
then new blood vessels
それから新しい血管が
like just asked
ちょうど尋ねられたように
Alzheimer's Disease Wang Chujun
埃斯海默症王楚軍
They are all in the plan
それらはすべて計画の中にあります
very many diseases
非常に多くの病気
Not just chronic diseases
慢性疾患だけではない
Yes, the whole world is not only our Taiwan
そう、全世界は私たちの台湾だけではないのです
In collecting this so-called age-based
このいわゆる年齢ベースの収集では、
and keep track of them
そしてそれらを追跡してください
many places have
多くの場所にあります
I know it's like Europe
ヨーロッパっぽいのはわかるけど
they have a very large
彼らは非常に大きなものを持っています
Then they also recently asked
それから彼らは最近こう尋ねました
Should Taiwan participate?
台湾も参加すべきでしょうか？
But something from Taiwan
でも台湾から来たもの
As far as Taiwan's regulations are
台湾の規制に関して言えば、
Simplified cannot be sent out
簡易発送不可
so there is no way
だから仕方ない
The one in the European Union is
欧州連合のものは、
They can be exported in simplified form
簡略化された形式でエクスポートできます
So if I join that league today
だから今日そのリーグに参加したら
I can apply Simplified to analyze
簡略化を適用して分析できます
European Union
欧州連合
That's also in Hupo
それはヒューポにもあります
As for the Hupo I just mentioned
さっき言ったヒューポに関しては
We have signed the MOU
私たちはMOUを締結しました
Then Japan also has this small database
では、日本にもこの小さなデータベースがあります
There are also some in Japan
日本にもいくつかあるよ
other places
他の場所
I think Taiwan
台湾だと思う
Should be quite large
かなり大きいはずです
So I think this is a Taiwanese
だから台湾人だと思う
very important asset
非常に重要な資産
right
右
The one in Japan has been in business for 50 years
日本で創業50年
So I told Shen Zhiyang
そこで私は沈志陽に言いました。
You better live another 50 years
あと50年は生きたほうがいいよ
to support this database
このデータベースをサポートするために
50 years old
50年的
If you want to track a group
グループを追跡したい場合
50 years is not easy
50年って簡単じゃないよ
that's a very important asset
それはとても重要な資産です
May I ask the professor, how does cancer arise?
教授に聞いてもいいですか、がんはどのようにして発生するのでしょうか？
Thanks
ありがとう
Maybe I'm not the best person to answer
もしかしたら私は答えるのに適した人間ではないかもしれません
is there any
何かありますか
Maybe we should invite Principal Yang Tengci to explain
楊騰慈校長を招いて説明してもらうべきかもしれない
I say it like this
私はそう言います
There are many, many causes of cancer
がんの原因は本当にたくさんあります
That is, it may be like the mutation of the gene I just mentioned
つまり、先ほど言った遺伝子の突然変異のようなものかもしれません。
A genetic change is a
遺伝子の変化というのは、
like many so-called autocancers
多くのいわゆる自己がんと同様に
Genes that cause cancer are well known
がんの原因となる遺伝子はよく知られている
that protein will also
そのタンパク質も
But in the end then this happened
でも最後にはこうなりました
related to environmental factors
環境要因に関連する
like i just said about smoking
先ほど喫煙について言ったように
And that one, a woman who gave birth to a D child very late.
そしてその方は、かなり遅くにDの子を出産した女性です。
Cancer is relatively intense is high
がんの強度が比較的高い
many environmental factors
多くの環境要因
but if you want to ask
でも聞きたいなら
Which is the main reason
主な理由はどれですか
no standard answer
標準的な答えはありません
Like that Lee Harvey just now
まさに今のリー・ハーヴェイのように
when he came to taiwan
彼が台湾に来たとき
We held a careful workshop
丁寧なワークショップを開催しました
Then I asked him
それから私は彼に尋ねました
because they america do everything
彼らはアメリカが何でもするから
This gene sports also do
この遺伝子スポーツもやります
Agents also do
エージェントもやります
do everything
すべてをする
ask him
彼に尋ねる
Which is the most important molecule in nature
自然界で最も重要な分子はどれですか
he said his statement was funny
彼は自分の発言が面白いと言った
He said that so far there is no standard answer
彼は、今のところ標準的な答えはないと述べた
so everyone doesn't know
だからみんなは知らない
So each one should be done
したがって、それぞれを実行する必要があります
this is his answer
これが彼の答えです
So there are many causes of his cancer
つまり、彼の癌には多くの原因がある
that seems to have a theory that says
という理論があるようです
you have some so-called cancer stem cells in your body
あなたの体内にはいわゆるがん幹細胞がいくつかあります
he hides over there
彼はあそこに隠れています
Then when environmental factors come out
そうすると環境要因が出てくると
he is activated
他就被活化
There is also such a saying
こんな言い伝えもあります
May ask Yang to rebel
ヤンに反乱を要請するかもしれない
He is better suited to answer this question
彼はこの質問に答えるのに適している
this professor chen
このチェン教授は
you start researching
あなたは研究を始めます
I've been thinking about it now, there's no skipped stitches
今考えてみたら、目飛びなんてないよ
And the speech and the setting are all normal.
そして、スピーチと設定はすべて正常です。
Didn't start coughing until 93 minutes
咳は93分まで出なかった
then i want to ask a question now
それでは今から質問したいのですが
ask a question
質問する
Now we know all about Genesis
これでジェネシスについてすべてがわかりました
But cancer is still a mystery
しかし、がんは依然として謎に包まれています
Maybe we have a better understanding of the topic we just talked about
もしかしたら、今話したトピックについての理解が深まったかもしれません
protein analysis
タンパク質分析
Come as once Hanayama cancer time
花山ガンタイム一度来てください
It is more reliable to track its treatment
治療を追跡する方が信頼性が高い
is it possible
出来ますか
We are now old people looking forward to
私たちは今、楽しみにしている老人です
Inside this protein study
このタンパク質研究の内部
more thorough words
もっと徹底した言葉を
Huashan who can control this cancer
このガンを制御できる華山
is it possible
出来ますか
of course it is possible
もちろん可能です
We'd love to get to this point
ここまで到達したいと思っています
so we're doing some
それで私たちはいくつかのことをやっています
just doing some analysis
ただ分析を行っているだけです
For example, when we first arrived
たとえば、私たちが初めて来たとき
We have some cooperation with Academician Chen Peizhe
私たちはアカデミー会員のChen Peizhe氏と協力しています。
We hope that with Teacher Yang Fuliang
ヤン・フリアン先生と一緒にそれを願っています
some are doing together
一緒にやってる人もいる
It is hoped that some molecules can be found in the blood of newly arrived patients for testing
検査のために新しく到着した患者の血液中にいくつかの分子が見つかることが期待されている
Then Teacher Yang Fuliang and the others are doing the super fast one
それからYang Fuliang先生と他の人たちは超高速の練習をしています
Reagents that can be tested at home
自宅で検査できる試薬
that small instrument
その小さな楽器
That's not good at talking
あれは話すのが苦手だ
kit
キット
right
右
Am looking forward to
楽しみにしています
and certification
および認証
right
右
We would love to be able to reach the internal
内部まで到達できれば幸いです
so we should have that
だから私たちはそれを持つべきです
Find that Guo Dong through the relationship
関係を通じて郭東を見つける
Guo Dong today more than 100 National Taiwan University to do IZEN
郭東氏は今日、100人以上の国立台湾大学がIZENを行う予定です
Why not come and do our blank paper research
白紙調査に来てみませんか
actually
実際
In fact, I think there are some three-season industries over there.
実際、向こうにはスリーシーズン産業もいくつかあると思います。
but
しかし
I think it's a pity
残念だと思います
sorry to say
いいにくいのですが
Taiwan's biotech industry is small
台湾のバイオテクノロジー産業は小規模です
So they make sure you develop it to a very mature stage
したがって、彼らはそれを非常に成熟した段階まで開発するようにします
For example, five hundred people
たとえば、500人
The result is very sure that they are willing to become a class
結果は、彼らがクラスになりたいと思っていることを非常に確信しています
At the very early stage of so-called development
いわゆる開発のごく初期の段階で
no one wants to give you money
誰もあなたにお金をあげたくありません
The Central Plains Institute is willing to give us the
セントラルプレーンズ研究所は喜んで私たちに提供します。
thank you very much tonight
今夜はありがとうございました
Thanks
ありがとう
You are probably doomed to eat more when you are born
あなたはおそらく生まれたときにもっと食べるように運命づけられています
You ate too much earlier, you just explained
先ほど食べすぎました、説明したばかりです
eat less
食べる量を減らす
Did my professor just say a statistic
私の教授は今統計について言及しましたか?
Is it right now that I read some books
今、本を読んでいますか？
He said that a person is born like a car
彼は「人は車のように生まれる」と言いました
You probably use a lot of connections
おそらく多くの接続を使用していると思われます
probably fixed
おそらく修正されました
You just say about this
あなたはこれについてだけ言います
Is there a corresponding saying that a person is like this
人はこうであるというそれに相当する諺はありますか
You can roughly explain or eat too much has a fixed
ざっくり説明したり、食べすぎは決まっています
Because I can still calculate this data
まだデータ計算できるから
This is probably not possible from a scientific point of view.
これはおそらく科学的な観点からは不可能です。
but i can only say
でも言えることは
You take good care of your body, take care of your daily routine and do a good job
体に気を付けて、日々の生活に気をつけて、頑張ってね
it must be ok
きっと大丈夫です
Of course another angle is
もちろん別角度も
I'm still full of trust in things I can't see
目に見えないものを信じ続ける
There are things that science can't explain
科学では説明できないことがある
man's fate
男の運命
Is it a well-structured network?
適切に構造化されたネットワークですか?
I personally believe it
私は個人的にそれを信じています
it's not science
それは科学ではありません
This is not the angle of the flaming meatball
これは燃えるミートボールの角度ではありません
Yes but in this way
はい、でもこの方法で
That is to say, use this biochemical method to do this thing
つまり、このことを行うにはこの生化学的手法を使用します
currently there is no way
現時点では方法がありません
We can only measure these
私たちが測定できるのはこれらだけです
Whether protein or gene
タンパク質か遺伝子か
It actually just tells you an instant status
実際には即座にステータスを知らせるだけです
that sample
そのサンプル
Or if I draw your blood now
あるいは、今あなたの血を採ったら
I will test
テストします
I just detected your current state
あなたの現在の状態を発見しました
but i can't tell you
でも言えない
what's your future
あなたの将来は何ですか
or how you used to be
または以前はどうでしたか
We can only measure your current state
私たちが測定できるのはあなたの現在の状態だけです
So this problem is still rare
したがって、この問題はまだまれです
You seem to be talking about the world of spirits, right?
どうやら霊界の話をしているようですね？
that too big effect
そのあまりにも大きな効果
you laugh so hard that he thinks
あなたがあまりにも大笑いするので、彼はこう思う
There is also something about listening to the professor
教授の話を聞くのもありです
also believe so
私もそう信じています
i like to read some other books
他の本を読むのが好きです
I can't say too much about my identity today
今日は自分のアイデンティティについてあまり多くを語ることはできません
It's okay, professor, I'll ask for advice
大丈夫です、先生、アドバイスをお願いします
So what we just mentioned is
それで、私たちが今述べたことは、
The professor has about this software data analysis aspect
教授はこのソフトウェアデータ分析の側面について話しています
So we are currently in Taiwan to test
それで現在台湾でテストする予定です
For example, Mr. Tanaka
たとえば、田中さん。
Mr. Donnakar, they pour gold
ドナカールさん、彼らは金を注ぎます
What is worth the capabilities of this developed technology
この開発されたテクノロジーの機能の価値は何ですか
Has our current Taiwan caught up?
今の台湾は追いついてきたのか？
when you are researching
研究しているとき
In the use of this instrument is there
この楽器の使用には次のようなものがあります
That's what they're making
それが彼らが作っているものです
Has been making analysis faster and more accurate
分析をより迅速かつ正確に行っています
In fact, this problem is our field
実はこの問題は私たちの分野です
a big challenge
大きな挑戦
Because the cost of paper Puyi is actually quite expensive
溥儀の紙は実はかなり高価なので
a general instrument
一般的な楽器
Maybe 20 to 30 million
たぶん2000～3000万くらい
So when your instrument comes out
だからあなたの楽器が出てきたら
continue
続く
But from an academic point of view
しかし学術的な観点から見ると
Unlikely to keep buying new instruments
新しい楽器を買い続ける可能性は低い
so our
だから私たちの
My own thoughts are usually
私自身の考えは、通常、
what equipment do i have
私はどんな装備を持っていますか
what instrument do i use
私はどんな楽器を使いますか
Then what we hope is from
それでは、私たちが期待しているのは、
Maybe go from the methodology side
おそらく方法論の側面から行くでしょう
go do it well
行って上手にやってください
Of course, if Academia Sinica supports us very much
もちろん、中央研究院が私たちを大いにサポートしてくれるのであれば、
or the country is very supportive of us
あるいは国が我々を非常に支援してくれている
Give us constantly new instruments
常に新しい楽器を提供してください
that is of course ideal
それはもちろん理想的です
But I think Taiwan resources
でも台湾のリソースは
Going to talk to people like the United States or the mainland
アメリカや本土のような人々と話をしに行く
keep buying keep buying
買い続けます 買い続けます
we may have a little difficulty
少し難しいかもしれない
that information
その情報
In fact, Taiwan's information is very strong
実は台湾の情報力は非常に強いです
I think Taiwan's information is very strong
台湾の情報はとても強いと思います
Like our analysis software
弊社の分析ソフトウェアと同様に
Teacher Song Deyi Teacher Xu Weinian
ソン・デイイー先生 シュー・ウェイニアン先生
their software
彼らのソフトウェア
that is very
それはとても
That is, the level of analysis is very good
つまり、分析レベルは非常に優れています
I think the whole world
全世界だと思います
Must be the first few
最初の数個でなければなりません
Then there's that big data
それからビッグデータです
It is also a powerful
台湾でも有力な勢力です
So I think bioinformatics in Taiwan
それで私は台湾におけるバイオインフォマティクスだと思います
In fact, we can make good use of it
実はそれを上手に活用することができるんです
an advantage
一個優勢
As for the salary of the instrument
楽器の給料については
Or in Zhipuyi's research and development
あるいは知溥儀の研究開発においても
Actually in Taiwan
実は台湾では
some people are doing
何人かがやってる
Like Chen Zhongxuan and Academician Chen of Genome Center of Central Plains Institute
セントラルプレーンズ研究所ゲノムセンターのチェン・ジョンシュアン氏とアカデミー会員のチェン氏のように
He has done a very good job in the research and development of Zhipuyi
彼はZhipuyiの研究開発において非常に良い仕事をしました。
There is also a researcher Wang Yisheng
研究者の王宜生もいます
He is also doing instrument research and development
機器の研究開発も行っている
well done too
もよくやった
Today, it is also mentioned that he only started at 93 minutes
今日、彼は93分から先発出場したことにも言及されている
I'm coughing now
今咳をしています
let us thank chen
チェンに感謝しましょう
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました